宝贝老板
渡尽劫波兄弟在 相逢一笑泯恩仇
— 鲁迅
重操旧业
(人类的)
"时间感"十分奇妙
Time is a funny thing.
童年时 1
-When I was a kid... -One.
日子悠长 历历在目 2
-...the days lasted forever. -Two.
快藏起来 3
-Hide, hide, hide! -Three.
长大后 等等!躲来这
-But the years... -Wait! Over here.
平淡无趣 时光如梭 4
-...well, they went by so fast. -Four.
5 6 蒂姆,别偷看
-Five. Six. -Tim, no peeking.
对,别偷看
Yeah, no peeking.
不知不觉 7
-Before you know it... -Seven.
大家都成家立业了 8
-...you're all grown-up. -Eight.
我也不可避免 9
-It even happened to me. -Nine.
9.5 10!
Nine and a half. Ten!
藏好了吗 我来找你们了
Ready or not, here I come.
我叫蒂姆,下面…
My name's Tim, and this...
是我成家后的故事
well, this is the rest of my story.
"逃命"去吧!
Run for your lives!
不公平 爸爸你作弊
No fair, Dad. You peeked.
我绰号叫"全职主夫" 因为… 我们走!
-They call me a stay-at-home dad, which means... -Let's go!
…我把家里打理的井井有条 朝气蓬勃
...I hardly get to stay at home.
系好安全带,小邓普顿们
Buckle up, Templetons.
准备好了吗?
Ready?
系好了 出发!
-Set. -Go!
有人会觉得
Now, some might say
我想象力太丰富(戏精)
I still have an overactive imagination,
但 陪伴孩子成长是最酷的事
but being a dad is the coolest job in the world.
有很多好玩的活计
Bunch of cool jobs, really.
有时我是一个赛车手
Sometimes I'm a race car driver.
马里奥•安德烈蒂
Mario Andretti
有史以来最成功的赛车手之一
哇!爸爸是超级马里奥!
Whoo! Daddy-o Andretti!
耶,邓普顿家族!
Yay, Templetons!
有时
Well, and then sometimes
我又是县里最好的厨师
I'm the best darn cook in the county
每顿饭都由我来分发
and I deal out every meal.
爸,请发"牌"给我
Come on, Pa, hit me.
蒂娜
Tina.
呼,好家伙!庄家通杀
Whew, doggie! And the house wins again.
耶! 呜呼!
-Yay! -Woo-hoo!
也可以是外科医生
Or a surgeon, if need be.
叉勺 叉勺
-Spork. -Spork.
抹刀 抹刀
-Spatula. -Spatula.
(烹饪中使用的工具)
赐予我的造物生命!
Give my creature life!
它活过来了!
She's alive!
生活有好有坏 跌宕起伏
We have our ups, and we have our downs.
别急 看
No, no, no. Look. Look.
"咩咩"没事 看 耶!
-Lamb Lamb's okay. See? -Yay!
但我们总是一起面对
But we always stick together.
我的妻子,卡罗 奇迹啊!
-My wife, Carol. -It's a miracle!
她是家里的经济支柱
She's the breadwinner of the family.
谢谢大家!你懂的
Thank you. You know what they
"和气生财"
"It's all about the dough."
丈夫的支持促成了我今天的成就
And I couldn't have done it without my husband.
他真是个"贤内助"
He really rose to the occasion.
这是我力所能及的 是的 妈妈!
-It's the yeast I can do. -Yeah, Mama!
她挣钱养家
She brings home the bacon, too,
我照看孩子
while I keep an eye on our new baby, Tina.
有时,感觉蒂娜像是
But sometimes, feels like
她在蹬着我
she's keeping an eye on me.
塔比莎…谢谢!
-And Tabitha... -Thank you!
橡子中学
就读初二的大女儿
...our little second-grader who just got accepted
橡子中学
考上了城里最好的学校
into the best school in town.
好样的,塔比莎!
Yay, Tabitha!
我们以你为荣
We're so proud.
我昔日的小团伙还没解散
I still keep in touch with the old gang, too.
信不信由你,金博现在是市长了
Believe it or not, Jimbo is mayor now.
饼干! 自然,他的"贤内助"
-Cookie! -Of course, his wife, Staci,
丝塔奇女士足智多谋
is the real brains behind the operation.
哟,吉米! 而"三胞胎"兄弟…
-Yo, Jimbo! -Now, the Triplets...
♪逮…♪到…
-♪ Busted... -♪ Busted...
♪你
-♪ Busted.
还是老样子
Yeah, they haven't changed much.
至于我弟弟,泰德
And as for my baby brother, Ted,
他成了大老板
well, he grew up to be the boss, all right.
他太忙了,我们很少见面
He's so busy we hardly see him anymore.
不过他还是会表露心意
But, hey, he always remembers
通过赠送夸张的礼物
to send inappropriately lavish gifts
在特殊场合
on special occasions.
我的天!泰德叔叔真懂我!
OMG! Uncle Ted is the best!
总而言之
All in all,
我的生活相当完美
my life is pretty perfect.
但一切即将改变
But all that was about to change.
天啊
Good heavens.
我来救你!
I'll save you!
哈!
Ha!
谢谢你,宝贝
Thanks, babe.
保持冷静,塔比莎
Stay calm, Tabitha.
我来救你了
I'm coming for you.
我要把你从熔岩中救出来!
I'm gonna save you from the bubbling lava!
爸爸,你在干什么?
Dad, what are you doing?
呕 这东西洒了一地
Ew, gross. It went everywhere.
拜托,这是"糖果火山"!
Come on, this is the candy volcano of doom!
你以前很喜欢的
You used to love it.
但我得专心做作业
But I'm trying to do my homework,
不然我就完了
or I'm doomed.
哦
Oh.
我唯一确定的是
Because if there's one thing I've learned,
童年只有一次
you're only a kid once.
时光一去不复还
Once you grow up, you can never go back.
哦,不
Oh, no.
晚安"霍金博士"
Good night, Dr. Hawking.
碳 硼 铍 锂 氦 氢
Carbon, boron, beryllium, lithium, helium, hydrogen.
搞定
Nailed it.
♪ Boom shakalaka.
Boom shakalaka.
"Fantastic baby"中的歌词
指模拟灌篮的声音
(剔牙线 喂鱼 背元素周期表 看课本)
四项任务 事半功倍
"Carry the four." Gosh.
嘿,塔比莎
Hey there, Tabitha.
"晚安秀"时间
It's The Good Night Show.
在卧室直播,由爸妈主演
Live from your bedroom, starring Dad and Mom.
特别嘉宾,宝贝蒂娜
And special guest, baby Tina.
晚安,蒂娜!
Good night, little Tina. Mwah!
你给我回来
Come back here, you.
晚安,妈妈
Good night, Mom.
晚安,甜心
Good night, sweetheart.
我得好好疼你
Mama gonna kiss you.
"晚安歌"
Good night song
爸爸演唱 什么?
-With your dad... -What?
怎么?唱歌时间啊
What? It's time for your good-night song.
哦,今天不用了
Oh, no, thanks.
我现在听白噪音
I'm listening to white noise!
能助睡!
Helps me fall asleep!
嘿 要不
Hey, what would you say
让我帮你排练节目?
to me helping you rehearse for the holiday pageant?
好主意 是吧
Yes! Right?
我可以和你一起去学校,
I can come to school with you, and you can get
和你的朋友们一起排练节目
all your friends together, and we can rehearse together,
之后去吃冰淇淋
go get some ice cream after.
我请客 不!不行
-My treat. -No! You can't do that.
我想靠自己完成
Um, liability issues.
整个节目
It's this whole thing.
哦 好吧
Oh. Right, right.
好…
Right.
你最爱的睡前故事要听吗
Whoa. How about your favorite bedtime story?
你知道的,关于…
You know, the one about...
泰德叔叔是个会说话的神奇宝宝
Uncle Ted was a magical talking baby.
有一个装满小狗的火箭
There was a rocket full of puppies,
你拯救了世界
and you saved the world.
精彩的故事,对吧?
It was a good story, wasn't it?
额,就是有点扯
Well, it didn't really make a lot of sense.
不过还是很有趣吧
The jokes were good, right?
嗯哼
Mm.
好吧 爸爸
-Okay. Um... -Dad.
我想早点睡 明天有很多事
My schedule is brutal tomorrow.
我也是 明天要早起
Yeah. My schedule's pretty brutal, too.
别忘了"咩咩"
Oh, don't forget Lamb Lamb.
晚安,"咩咩"
Good night, Lamb Lamb.
晚安,泰德叔叔
Good night, Uncle Ted.
我希望长大后能像你一样成功
I hope to grow up and be a success, just like you.
也许我们很快就能见面
Maybe we'll see you soon.
晚安,塔比莎
Good night, Tabitha.
你不觉得那很幼稚吗
Don't you think I'm a little old for that now?
呃,好吧
Uh, okay.
给彼此一点空间
I think it's time we both grow up.
我会早起做早餐 你多睡会吧
I look forward to greeting you at the breakfast table.
祝你做美梦
Sweet dreams.
嗯
Hmm.
昔日的时光都去哪了?
Where has the time gone?
我怎么会知道?
How should I know?
等下 我看到光了
Wait, wait. I see light.
快滚开
You, oh, out of my way.
终于
At long last.
自由的空气
The sweet breath of freedom.
威兹?
Wizzie?
嘿 这是哪个世纪?
You there, what century is this?
放开我,邪恶的食人魔!
Unhand me, vile ogre!
威兹 是我啊
No, no, no, no. Wizzie, it's me.
我是蒂姆
It's Tim.
真的吗?
Is it really you?
靠过来一点
Come closer.
让我看看你的脸
Let me see your face.
在近点
Closer.
更近一点
Closer still.
哦,蒂莫西
Oh, Timothy.
是你啊
It is you.
嘿! 为啥打我?
Hey! What was that for?
你把我丢进了永恒的黑暗
You cast me into eternal darkness
破坏了我的计时功能
and wreaked havoc on my circadian rhythms.
对不起,威兹
I'm sorry, Wizzie.
嘿 你保存的很好
Hey, but you look great, though.
断臂让我美中不足
Except for the arm, you mean.
我都没注意到
I didn't even notice.
-你看不见? -我是说,我注意到了
-You thought it. -I mean, I noticed it,
这很明显 我只是不想
'cause I... you obviously don't have an arm. I-I...
你绝不会这样对"咩咩"的
You would never treat Lamb Lamb this way.
我把它给了我女儿,塔比莎
Well, I... I gave her to my daughter, Tabitha.
你有继承人了吗,蒂莫西?
You have produced an heir, Timothy?
两个孩子呢
Two, actually.
两个? 敲钟庆祝吧!
Two? Let the bells ring!
不,不 威兹,停下来 太好了!
-No, no, no. Wizzie, stop. -Yes! Yes!
威兹,嘘!安静 这是欢庆的时刻!
-Wizzie, shh! Quiet, quiet. -It's a time for celebration!
别 现在大家都在睡觉
No, no, no. It's not the time for celebration.
威兹,嘘 保持安静 什么?它是什么?
-Wizzie, shh. Be quiet. -What? What is it?
怎么了,蒂姆? 我不知道
-What is it, Tim? -I don't know.
我今天有点失落
I guess I'm just not feeling
不想庆祝
very celebratory right now.
哦?
Oh?
塔比莎
Tabitha.
老兄,她长得真快
Man, Wizzie, she's growing up so fast.
好像已经不需要我了
It's like she doesn't even need me anymore.
对,首先,他们冷落你
Yes, first, they start spending less time with you.
接着 不再向你寻求建议
Then they stop coming to you for advice.
正是
Exactly.
然后 认为你无关紧要
Soon, they take you for granted.
可能吧
I guess.
之后打断你的胳膊 什么?
-Then break your arm. -What?
最后把你抛之脑后!
Then stuff you into a box!
威兹,你在帮倒忙
Okay. Wizzie, you're... you're not helping.
我只是…害怕
Okay, I'm just... I'm afraid
塔比莎和我会渐行渐远
Tabitha and I are growing apart,
…就像我和泰德一样
like... like I did with my brother.
哦
Oh.
我还在感今惟昔
I thought we had all the time in the world.
但你不能回到过去,对吧?
But you can't turn back time, can you?
你竟敢质疑我的力量!
How dare you question my power!
"时光倒流" 又来了
-Turn back. Turn back. -Oh, here we go.
伟大的时间之轮… 等
-Oh, great wheel of li... -Wait.
你听到了吗?
Did you hear that?
别乱用"贪睡"按钮!
Never abuse the snooze button!
声音像是从宝宝房传来的
It sounds like it's coming from the baby's room.
是个夜行性生物?
What is it? A creature of the night?
女巫吗?还是地狱之犬的叫声?
Witches? Is it the baying of the hounds of hell?
威兹!
Wizzie!
别去,蒂姆!
Don't go, Tim!
我可以让时光倒流
I can turn back time--
到只有你和我的黄金岁月
to the golden years, when it was just you and me.
我的胳膊
My good arm.
别开门
Don't open the door.
还记得上次吗!
Remember last time!
如果你想致电
If you would like to make a call,
请挂断再试一次
please hang up and try again.
如果你需要帮助,请挂机,然后拨总机
If you need help, hang up and then dial your operator.
谢谢你!
Thank you.
喂?
Hello?
如果你想致电
If you would like to make a call,
请挂断再试一次 啊 只是我的电话
-please hang up and try again. -Ah. Just my phone.
振作起来,伙计
Get it together, man.
蒂娜,你这个小偷…
Oh, Tina, you little klepto...
晚安
Nighty night.
…疯子!
...maniac!
哇!
Whoa!
嗨,爹地
Hi, Daddy.
蒂娜?是你吗?
T-Tabitha? Is that you?
看你吓成啥样啦
You should've seen your face.
太值了
Oh, it's priceless.
你…你…
You're... You... You-you...
你可以说话了?
You-you can talk?
是的 我在上班
Yep. I'm in the family business.
这领带是假的
It's a clip-on tie.
你要知道宝宝公司…
You see, Daddy, BabyCorp is more of what I...
哦
Oops.
爸爸 你能听到我说话吗?
Daddy, Daddy, come in. Can you hear me?
听得到吗?
Daddy, do you read me?
爸爸,这是几?
Daddy, how many fingers am I holding up?
星期四吗?
Thursday?
我应该先提醒你的
I should've given you a warning.
我还以为你很酷
I forgot you were an old man.
等等
Wait, wait.
你是宝贝公司的? 嗯
-You're from BabyCorp? -Yes.
宝宝公司更像是
BabyCorp is more of what I call
我的副业 嗯哼
-a side hustle for me. -Uh-huh.
我的主业是邓普顿家族
The point is I'm all in on the Templetons.
邓普顿加油! 哦!好吧
-Go, Templetons! -Oh! Okay.
你们居然那么了解宝宝
You guys really know how to baby a baby.
真是不可思议 哦,哦
-I mean, it's incredible. -Oh, oh.
也不是完美无缺
Not that's it's all five-star.
我不得不说,你有很多问题 当然
-I have to say, you got a lot of issues. -Sure. Yeah.
这个稍后在详聊
We'll talk about that later.
哦,天啊 我真不敢相信
Oh, my gosh. I can't believe this.
想去吓一下妈妈吗?
Hey, want to go scare the crap out of Mom?
爹地,请集中精神
Daddy, please stay focused. Oh.
对,对,对
Right, right, right.
宝宝公司出现了危机
There's a crisis at BabyCorp.
这次又怎么了?
What is it this time?
小猫?
Kittens?
不 这一次,情况更糟
No. This time, it's even worse.
比上次还糟?嗯
-Worse than kittens? -Yes.
所以我才自愿加入
That's why I volunteered for
这绝密的任务 妈妈
-this supersecret assignment. -Mommy.
哦,我想帮忙 我该怎么做?
Ooh, I want to help. What-what do you want me to do?
就是要这种干劲
That's the spirit, Daddy.
你正是我需要的人 好的!
-You are exactly who I need. -Yes!
去找泰德叔叔
To get Uncle Ted.
不 什么?
No. What?
你这是什么表情?
What-What's with the face?
爸爸,宝宝公司不能再等了
Daddy, BabyCorp can't wait any longer.
所有的压力都在我身上,爸
All the pressure's on me, Pop.
当我自愿参加这项工作时
When I volunteered for this gig,
我以为会很容易
I thought it would be easy.
但你们俩从不联系
But you two never see each other.
真可悲
It's so sad.
就像 "不及格 留堂"
It's like, "F-minus. See me after class."
可悲? 或许吧
Sad? Uh, yeah, maybe.
有点 我不确定
A little. I don't know.
我不是让你打电话给他吗?
Did you forget to call him?
我发现你有点心不在焉
I noticed you can be a little absentminded.
你说什么?
Sorry, what?
我说你有拖延症
It's just that you tend to procrastinate.
你得让他来家里过节
You have to get him here for the holidays.
不,我还没…
No, I'm not...
不,我等会再打
No, I'm not gonna call him right now.
-拖延症老爸 -别
-Daddy, can't never could. -No.
你俩吵架了? 发生了什么?
Did you two have a fight or something?
没 你对他有怨气?
-No. -But you're mad at him?
别打了 说来话长
Stop that. It's complicated.
打个电话不就搞清楚了?
Why? Do you need help using your phone?
我自己会解决
No, I don't need help using my...
好 问题在哪?
Okay. What's the problem?
告诉我
What's the issue? Talk to me.
打了也没用
There's no point, okay?
我打电话邀请他 他从不来
I call him. I invite him. He never shows up.
他总是要参加工作会议或出差
He's always got a work meeting or a business trip
或者是电话会议
or a conference call.
他只关心工作
All he cares about is work.
时间长了就不想联系了
But after a while, you... you just stop trying.
他还是你兄弟
He's still your brother.
你俩是合作伙伴
You were partners.
对,可是长大后…
Yeah, I guess sometimes you just...
我成家 他立业
you grow up and grow apart.
别放弃 爹地
Daddy, don't say no.
如果大家都轻言放弃
What if everybody said no?
奇迹就不会发生
Nothing would happen.
九层之台 起于累土
Nothing would get off the ground.
太阳每天照常升起
You got to wake up every day
你得乐观一点
and you got to say, "Yes, yes, yes!"
让我刮目相看吧
Surprise me. Say yes.
这真令人失望
This is really disappointing.
现在我很生气! 不早了
-And now I'm getting mad! -It's late.
我们明天再商量,好吗?
We can work on this tomorrow, okay?
哦 你的玩具掉下来了
Oh. Whoopsie. Your little horsey fell off.
不急这一晚,对吧?
Another day won't hurt, right?
晚安,亲爱的
Good night, sweetie.
…"独角兽"掉了
...horsey fell off.
塔比莎?
Tabitha?
嗯?
Huh?
不用管 我来开门
Uh, don't worry. I got it.
她在哪里呢?哪里?
Where is she? Where is she?
你说谁? 我已经尽快赶来了
-Where's who? What? -I came as fast as I could.
泰德? 我推掉了会议行程
-Ted? -I canceled all my meetings.
你来干什么? 讲什么?
What are you doing here? Why are you yelling?
塔比莎呢? 塔比莎?
-Where's Tabitha? -Tabitha?
蒂姆呢? 泰德叔叔
-Where is she, Tim? -Ted.
泰德叔叔,你真的来了!
Uncle Ted, you're here! You're really here.
是哪只手臂? 嗯?
-Which arm is it? Left or right? -Huh?
是小腿吗?和我讲 啊
-Is it your fibula? Talk to me. -Whoa.
腓骨
fibula
下肢小腿长骨之一
瞳孔正常 睁眼
Good dilation. Open up.
张嘴 你没事吧? 你在干什么?
-Say, "Ah." Are you okay? -Wh-What are you doing?
-你没受伤啊 -嗯?
-You look okay. -Whoa.
别担心 我很好 叔叔
Don't worry. I'm fine, Uncle Ted.
命真硬 哦吼
-That's my girl. -Woo-hoo.
什么风把你吹来了?
Uh, wh-what brings you into town?
塔比莎从马上摔下来了
Well, Tabitha fell off her pony.
有吗? 是吗?
-She did? -She did?
我没吧?
I did?
蒂姆给我留了语音留言 他?
-Tim left me a voice mail. -He did?
我? 是啊
-I did? -You did.
嘿 兄弟是我
Hello. This is your brother.
快来帮我 塔比莎从马上摔了下来
Help. Tabitha fell off horsey.
晚安,亲爱的
Good night, sweetie.
这真让人费解
Well, that was unsettling.
我发誓没留言
I swear I didn't leave that message.
…无意的
On... purpose.
我…
I...
不小心按错?
Butt-dialed?
用我的屁股
With my butt.
在我说梦话的时候
While I was talking in my sleep.
之前发生过
I do that sometimes.
这都能给我留言?
You sleep-butt-dialed me?
用我的屁股
With my butt.
这肯定得有个合理的解释
I knew there must be a perfectly logical explanation.
是乌龙事件
And there it is.
嗯 你终于来家做客啦
-Hmm. -All that matters is that you're here.
啊!耶!
Woo-hoo! Yay!
是啊 额,暂时是
Absolutely. Uh, for now.
泰德叔叔,请留下来过圣诞节
Uncle Ted, please stay for Christmas. Please.
对不起,小宝贝 25号我有安排
Sorry, sweetie. I can't do Christmas on the 25th.
但是,泰德叔叔,我很想你
But, Uncle Ted, I missed you so much.
好久没见你了
I missed you so much.
我好想你…
你不觉得那很幼稚吗
Don't you think I'm a little old for that now?
我不在是小孩了
(请给我独立自主的空间)
Don't you think I'm a little old for that now?
我能和你去厨房谈谈吗?
Can I talk to you in the kitchen?
就我们俩
Alone.
"宝贝",蒂姆?
The baby, Tim?
她是被那里派来的
She's been sent from up there.
-楼上吗? -对 "宝贝公司"
-Upstairs? -That's right. BabyCorp.
语音求助是"宝宝公司"留的?
So you're saying the voice mail was some kind of call for help.
是的!不
Yes! No.
她来自一个由宝宝经营的秘密公司
She comes from a secret corporation run by babies.
蒂姆,我给你介绍个医生
Tim, I'm gonna give you the name of a doctor.
罗伊费德 让他给你好好看看
Roy Federman. Just tell him I sent you, okay?
他们在讲什么?
What are they saying?
我们应该给他们点私人空间
We should give them some privacy.
-拿着 -哦 谢谢
-Here you go. -Ooh. Thanks.
我没疯!
I'm not crazy!
你只是忘了 告诉他,蒂娜
You just don't remember. Tell him, Tina.
-他… -宝宝不会讲话
-He... I... -She can't talk, Tim.
别插话
Stop interrupting.
宝宝不说话 你有幻听吧
Interrupting what? I don't hear anything.
你的声音可是异常刺耳呢
Except your obnoxious voice. You hear that.
(我可是全厂最好的播音员)
我的嗓音条件可好了
I have a beautiful voice.
等着
Fine.
我会证明这一切都是真的
I can prove that everything I'm saying is real.
是么? 对!
-Oh, yeah? -Yeah!
吸吮(奶嘴)
Suck it, Ted.
你说什么?
I beg your pardon?
你吸一下
You, suck.
不,还是你来吧
No, no, Tim. You suck.
是时候去买圣诞树啦
Time to go buy a Christmas tree.
家里不是有了吗
But we already have a Christmas tree.
不,我们没有 有啊
-No, we don't. No, we don't. -Yes, we do. Yes, we do.
快点吸…
Suck it, suck it, suck it, suck it, suck it, suck it.
把那东西移开! 打扰一下
-Get that pacie out of my face! -Excuse me.
我也不想这样 但能提个建议吗?
I hate to interrupt, but may I make a suggestion?
为啥你俩不一起吸
Why don't you both suck it?
哈!
Ha!
她能讲话 很会讲
-She can talk. -A lot.
准备好
Buckle up, boys.
出发啦!
Baby on board!
懂了吗 我说的对吧
That's what I'm talking about! Woo-hoo!
是啊!
Yeah! Woo-hoo!
哇
Wow.
我回来了
I'm home.
看到了吧
Yeah. See?
我没撒谎
It's all real.
哇
Whoa.
那是我吗?
Is that me?
如果你渴望得到赞颂 那么你如愿了
If you're fishing for a compliment, you caught one!
你是这里的传奇人物
You are a legend in this joint.
一座雕像?
A statue?
是我单枪匹马拯救了公司
Well, I did single-handedly save the company.
双塔奇兵
Double-handedly.
我们是合作伙伴
Right? We were partners.
真的吗?
Really?
我没看到你的雕像
I don't see your statue.
我仍然爱你,爸爸
I still love you, Daddy.
雕像头部比例太大了
They got the head size right.
相信我,你得要有野心
Take it from me, you have to be aggressive
如果你想取得成功
if you want to get ahead.
得拼搏 勇攀高峰
Climb that corporate ladder
直到会当凌绝顶 一览众山小 哇
-until you're the last baby standing at the top. -Wow.
我只想保持工作和生活的平衡
Actually, I prioritize a good work-life balance
开放乐观的氛围 重视人才
and a positive environment where my ideas are valued.
你说真的?
Oh, you're serious.
你真有趣 叔叔
You're funny, Uncle Ted.
为什么你的档案里没提到这一点
I wonder why they didn't mention that in your file.
我的资料?
My file?
你看过我档案?
You saw my file?
对啊 都写了什么?
-Yep. -What does it say?
讲了很多
It says a lot.
这里是危机处理中心 哇
-This is the Crisis Center. -Whoa. Wow.
是我们监控"宝宝危机"的地方
This is where we monitor all threats
为了全世界的宝宝
to babies around the world.
以及夏威夷
And Hawaii.
这太酷了 这太酷了
This is so cool. This is so cool.
我是哥斯拉
I'm Godzilla.
"快逃命吧!"
"Oh, run for your lives! Run for your lives!"
为什么要带他来? 爸爸,快下来
-Why did we bring him? -Daddy, get down from there.
哦 待会没人的时候再玩
-Aw. -We can play on it later when no one is looking.
都有什么危机? 哦
-What's the crisis? -Yeah.
开始吧 都有什么危机,亲爱的?
Here we go. What's the crisis, sweetie?
"锈锈" 播放
Rusty, roll it.
他新来的
He's new.
想象一下,宝宝外科医生
DR. Just imagine, baby surgeons.
哦
Uh-oh.
或宝宝宇航员
Or baby astronauts.
遨游~(宇宙)
Floaty, floaty, float.
总有一天宝宝会统治世界
Yes, babies are gonna run the world one day.
这一天来得比你想象的要早
And that day is coming sooner than you think.
你好 我是欧文•阿姆斯特朗博士
Hello. My name is Dr. Erwin Armstrong,
橡子高级儿童中学的创始人
founder of The Acorn Center for Advanced Childhood.
等一下,那是…塔比莎的学校
Wait a minute, that's... that's Tabitha's school.
在这里,我们相信宝宝
Here at the center, we believe babies
是终极学习机器
are the ultimate learning machines.
对吧,小内森?
Isn't that right, little Nathan?
-是啊! -不错
-Yeah! -Okay.
他们应该分秒必争
They should use their precious time
突飞猛进 发奋图强
to develop faster, push harder.
-嗯 -父母,他们都是
-Hmm. -Parents, they have the best
望子成龙,但他们不是专家
intentions, of course, but they're not experts.
毕竟,唯一阻碍孩子成长的是…
After all, the only thing holding your child back is...
你 你!
-you. -You!
这就解释了为什么塔比莎一直远离我
This explains why Tabitha's been pulling away from me.
是学校 每个人
-It's the school. -Everybody, wave.
再见,妈妈 再见,妈妈!
-Bye, Mommy. -Bye, Mommy!
再见,爸爸 再见,爸爸!
-Bye, Daddy. -Bye, Daddy!
再会
Sayonara.
在过去的六个月里
Now, in the past six months,
这些学校如雨后春笋般在世界各地出现
these schools have been popping up all over the world.
呃,危机到底是什么?
Uh, so what's the problem?
学校就是问题所在
The school is the problem.
学校都是坏的
Yeah. School is evil.
不,爸爸,不能一概而论
No, Daddy, not all schools are evil.
就只有这个是 好的
-It's just this one, okay? -Okay.
如果博士的谬论继续传播
If Armstrong's philosophy keeps spreading,
这可能终结童年
it could be the end of childhood.
不
No.
童年是我一生中最糟糕的三年
Childhood was the worst three years of my life.
真可悲
That's so sad.
你只是没有好好体会过
You probably just didn't do it right.
-嗯? -嗯
-Huh? -Aw.
幸运的是,你可以重来一次
But luckily, you get a do-over.
第二次机会
A second chance.
我们开发了一种新的超级宝宝奶粉
BabyCorp has developed a new super-duper baby formula
能让大人变回宝宝
that can turn a grown-up back into a baby.
有樱桃汁 葡萄汁 橙汁和酸橙汁口味
We have it in cherry, grape, orange and lime.
真的吗? 等等 等等
-For real? -Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
你想让我回宝宝? 嘿,这是你最擅长的
-You want me to be a baby? -Hey, it's what you do best.
这样你就能潜入学校探查
So you can infiltrate the school and find out
阿姆斯特朗博士的阴谋
what Dr. Armstrong is really up to.
剩下的就交给"宝宝公司"
BabyCorp will take care of the rest.
这是完美的伪装
It's the perfect disguise.
而且只持续了48个小时
And it only lasts 48 teensy-weensy hours.
我也参与了这次任务
Oh, I am in on the mission.
对不起,老爸
Sorry, Pops.
-你不能参加 -哦
-It's not your mission. -Aw.
"可能会导致流口水,胡言乱语
" may cause drooling, babbling,
心神不定 情绪失控
"emotional outbursts, fits of laughter,
大小便失禁,胃食管反流?
loss of bowel control, chubby thighs"?
我健身房里的人会吃这个
I think some guys at my gym take this stuff.
我这能干的小手!
My texting hand!
即使那是你女儿的学校
Even though it is your daughter's school.
真不公平,对吧?
Doesn't seem fair, does it?
爸爸,别(请)喝
Daddy, no. Please stop.
哇!
Whoa!
什么?它真的有用
What? It actually works.
它是我的!
It's mine!
-做宝宝我更擅长 -哦!
-I'm better with this kind of thing! -Oh!
刚才你变成了啥 海鸥群吗?
And what kind of thing is that, Flock of Seagulls?
青春药水 拿到了
-Everything! -Gotcha!
你可能会很情绪化,心神不宁
You might feel very emotional, have some mood swings.
哦!
Oh!
嘿!
Hey!
哎哟 尴尬的年龄段
Ouch. There's the awkward stage.
来喝茶,康妮
Now, the tea's hot, Connie.
你总是想当英雄,不是吗?
You always have to be the hero, don't you?
这话什么意思?
What's that supposed to mean?
从来不看望她…
Never see him...
送匹小马就成为我女儿的偶像
All of a sudden, he shows up with a pony.
你只是嫉妒,锅盖头
You're just jealous, helmet head.
她是我的女儿!
She's my daughter!
她是我的侄女
She's my niece.
你要加奶油或糖吗?
Do you want cream or sugar?
我总是成功的那个
I was always the successful one.
妈妈说不许在家里乱跑
Mommy says no running in the house.
胭脂鱼发型
Mullet
男子发型 前面和两侧的头发短 脑后的头发长
把药水给我,"鲻鱼头"
Hand over the bottle, mullet.
钱可不是万能的
You can't hug money, you know.
没钱可是万万不能的
But you can, Tim. You can.
争强好胜的男人
Men. Am I right?
这不是针对你
It's not personal.
公事公办而已
It's business, Leslie.
这是我的私事 林赛
Well, it's personal to me, Lindsey.
停 停! 喔 喔!
Stop, stop, stop, stop, stop! Ow, ow, ow!
抱歉 康妮 我得长话短说
I'm sorry, Connie. I have to cut this short.
我们明天在谈心
Tomorrow, we'll talk about your problems.
够了! 别闹了!
Okay, time-out! This has gone far enough!
嘿 我们回家了
Hey. We're home.
我们买了另一棵树
And we got another tree.
一棵真正的树
A real one.
现在快上楼
Um, upstairs now.
快,快,快
Go, go, go, go, go, go, go.
-推它 -不,拉
Push it. No, no, pull.
-快跑 -往里推
-Go, go, go, go, go. -Push it up.
拉 不 好吧
Pull. No, okay.
往右 为什么我头那么大?
-To the right. -How come I have the heavy end?
因为你年轻又强壮,亲爱的
Because you're young and strong, honey.
再来点
Little bit more.
我先!
Me first!
继续 放开我
-Come on. -Get off.
蒂姆? 泰德? 妈妈
-Tim? Ted? -Mom.
去拉绳
Get the cord. Get the cord.
快拉绳 上阁楼!
Get the cord, get the cord, get the cord!
你不能凭空消失
You just can't disappear.
你需要一个借口
You need a cover story.
噢! 是哦
-Ow! -Oh, right.
我的软肋
My soft spot.
你们在哪里?
Where are you guys?
说你在收拾行李
Uh, uh, tell her you're packing.
我们在楼上打包
We're upstairs, uh, packing.
打包?去哪?
Packing? For what?
哦 你要去参加兄弟情谊之旅
Ooh. You're going on a brother bonding trip.
我们要去兄弟情谊之旅 噢!
-We're going on a brother bonding trip. -Ow!
现在?
Now?
但是,蒂姆,你父母明天要来
But, Tim, your parents are coming tomorrow.
他们可以帮忙
They can help out.
是的,他们可以帮忙
Yeah, they could help out.
你不能留我一个人招待你父母
What... No, you can't leave me alone with your parents.
哦,蒂娜!
Oh, Tina!
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
够了 你要进宝宝监狱了
All right, you know what? You're going to baby jail.
哦,不,要倒了! 塔比莎!
-Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no! -Tabitha!
亲爱的,对不起 帮我个小忙
-Oh, honey, I'm sorry. -A little help here.
亲爱的 举起来 撑住
Honey, hold it up. Hold it up.
我是泰德•邓普顿
This is Ted Templeton, a man.
飞机可以走了 我这有家事要处理
You can go ahead and take off. I have urgent family business.
右边,亲爱的 对,我是有家室的人
-To the right, honey. -Yes, I have a family.
蒂姆,我要上来了
Tim, I'm coming up there.
我们得谈谈
Yeah, we need to talk.
嘿,妈妈?
Hey, Mom?
哦!蒂娜!
Oh! Tina!
把剪刀放下
Put that down. Put that down. Put that down.
快放下 蒂娜!
-Put that down. Put that down. -Tina!
放下! 到这来!
Put that down! Get back here!
蒂娜,快停下!
Tina, stop!
你发什么疯?
What has gotten into you?
我们该走了!
Time for us to go!
什么?现在? 是的
-What? Now? -Yeah.
并排停放
double-parked.
挡住了另一辆车的出路
飞机不能久留 再见!
-My helicopter's double-parked. -Bye!
等等 刚来就走? 哦,不
-Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait. So soon? -Oh, no.
不是说好要过圣诞节的吗
What... Did they really just leave?
是的
Yep.
快躲起来!
Hide!
婴儿肥真累人
I got to lose this baby fat.
蒂娜!你今天是咋了?
Tina! What is your problem?
现在,你明天醒来
Now, you're gonna wake up tomorrow
乖乖的,蒂娜
and be good, Tina.
别在捣乱了
No more devil baby.
好吗?
Deal?
好的
Okay.
"看光光"
Ew.
谢谢你们能来 "女士们"
Thanks so much for coming in, ladies.
想吃点水果吗?
Would you like some fruit?
嗯 噢!
Mm. Ow!
嘿!
Hey!
可以开始了吗?
Uh, can we get on with this?
想念我的牙齿
I miss my teeth.
我已经决定谁去执行任务了
I've decided who's going on the mission.
谢谢你!我接受
Thank you. I accept.
你们两个
Both of you.
太好了! 不
-Yes! -No.
公司想让我俩合作 是吧
BabyCorp wants to get the team back together, huh?
不
No.
他们认为这是个糟糕的主意
They think that's a terrible idea.
当然啦
Of course they do.
我说算 "苹果酱"
Well, I'm the boss, applesauce.
团结协作总比各自为战好
And I think you two are better together than you are apart.
我习惯一个人 至少不和他
Well, I work alone--or at least not with him.
"团队"中没有"我"
Hey. There's no "I" in "team."
"团队"里也没有"你"
Actually, there's no "U" in "team," either,
但有个"吾"
but there is an "M-E"  T-E-A-M...
你俩都不配合
But teamwork doesn't seem work.
如果你想成功 就得靠自己
Ah. If you want something done right, do it yourself.
我为人人 人人为我
-We're all in it together. -Every man for himself.
1是最孤独的数字
One is the loneliest number.
赞成的占多数 是赞成组团的
-The ayes have it. -We the people!
啊哈!
Aha!
哦 抱歉
Oh. So sorry.
好吧 晚安,各位
Okay. Good night.
唷
Whew.
看来我们只能把你的大雕像熔掉
Guess we'll just have to melt down your big old statue
然后把它变成参与奖品
and turn it into participation trophies.
求你了,别伤害我的雕像
Please, no, don't hurt my statue.
现在,我们有秘密情报
Now, we have secret intel
博士每天早上11点15分离开办公室
that Dr. Armstrong leaves his office every morning at 11:15.
你得偷偷溜进去
You need to sneak in there,
植入这些监控装置
plant these surveillance devices,
然后向我汇报
and report back to me.
天啊,这太酷了
Oh, man, this is so cool.
测试
Testing.
♪ Strangers in the night
by Frank Sinatra
♪黑夜里的陌生人…
♪ Strangers in the night...
我已经安排了一辆校车
Now, I've arranged for a school bus
早上8点整到这里!
to be here at 8:00 a.m. sharp!
谢谢,康妮 晚安
-Thank you, Connie. -Nighty night.
不要迟到
Do not be late.
明白了
Got it.
简简单单 小事一桩
Easy-breezy, taco-peasy, boys.
睡觉吧!
Let's get some sleep!
嘿,怎么了?
Hey, what's the matter?
没什么
It's nothing.
亲爱的,别担心
Oh, sweetie, don't worry.
我相信你爸爸会回来的
I'm sure your dad will be back
正好赶上你的表演
in time to see you in the pageant.
没关系
That's okay.
什么?你不想让他来吗?
What? Don't you want him to come?
可能吧 你只是觉得尴尬
-I guess. -Of course you do.
现在去睡觉吧
Now, go back to sleep.
晚安,妈妈
Good night, Mom.
晚安,亲爱的
Good night, sweetie.
你不想让他来吗?
Don't you want him to come?
大概吧
I guess.
我不在是小孩了
Don't you think I'm a little old for that now?
给彼此一点空间
I think it's time we both grow up.
蒂莫西•莱斯利•邓普顿的审判
The trial of Timothy Leslie Templeton
现在开庭
is now in session.
哈!莱斯利
Ha! Leslie.
审判?等等…罪名是什么?
Trial? Wait, what... what are the charges?
欺诈行为
Fraud.
声称自己是世上最好的父亲
Claiming to be the world's best dad.
我从没说过… 证物1
-But I never said... -Exhibit A.
世上最棒
父亲
不是吧 那是份礼物
Oh, come on. That was a gift.
你的辩护律师呢 被告不准发言
I suggest you let your attorney do the talking.
这明明是控方的人
Oh, no.
在我那个年代,你得自力更生
Back in my day, you had to earn one of these babies.
什么?我没有…
Dad, what? I did not...
他最好的朋友是个闹钟
His best friend was an alarm clock.
妈妈
Mom.
他打断了我的胳膊
He broke my arm.
没有! 是我弟弟干的
No, I didn't! It was my brother.
异议/反对
Objection
表示反对意见并要求法官即时作出裁决的行为
反对 法官大人
Objection, Your Honor.
一般法官会做出两种判决
"反对有效" "反对无效"
Sustained Overruled
反对有效
Sustained.
陪审团一致认为被告…
We the jury find the defendant...
是个失败者!
A failure!
塔比莎,能帮我说句话吗?
Tabitha, will you please help me out?
爸爸 学业不堪重负啊
Dad, the homework, it's just too much.
啊! 塔比莎!
-Whoa! -Tabitha!
时间到了
Time's up.
等等 爸爸! 救我!
-Wait. No! -Save me, Daddy! Save me!
哦 这梦够魔幻的
Oh, man. That was crazy.
我们睡过头了吗?
We overslept! We overslept?
睡过头了 醒醒 "哈比人"
-We overslept. -Wake up, little halflings!
现在是哪一年?
Wake up! What year is it?
哦,不
Oh, no.
情况不容乐观
This is bad. No.
不!不
No! No.
快起床
Get up.
快点 我们得走了
Get up. We got to go.
我们要迟到了…哦!
Come on. We're gonna be late for... Oh!
我会发邮件给你
I'm gonna email it to you.
这是怎么呢
What's going on?
我忘了把闹钟设为夏时制!
Ah, I forgot to set Wizzie for daylight savings!
夏令时/夏时制
Daylight Saving Time
人为将时间调快一小时 为了节约能源
啥? "日光"可不能"保存"
-What?! -Daylight can't be saved, Tim.
我得带上课堂用的植物和虫子
Oh, I got to get the plant and the bug we got to plant.
-我们得去赶车了 -不要恐慌
-Grab whatever. We got to go. -Don't panic. Do not panic.
…噢 祝你们成功
Ow. Godspeed, boys.
滑下去吧
Let's roll.
校服呢
Upsies.
我需要校服 哦!
-I need upsies...! -Oh!
穿好校服
Get dressed.
你对我做了什么?!
What have you done to me?!
这是啥衣服? 要去航海吗?
No, really? What, are we going sailing?
哦,不 校车要走了
Oh, no. No, no, it's leaving.
等等 快停下!
Wait, no, no. Stop!
停下 回来!
Stop, stop, stop. Come back!
喂!
Ahoy!
回来!
Come back!
"好极了"
Great, matey.
现在该怎么办?
What are we gonna do now?
哦,不!
Oh, no!
我高贵的宝贝骏马
Precious, my noble steed.
第一天上学可不能迟到 靠你啦
We must not be late for our first day of school.
哦,恶心
Oh, gross.
嗯?
Huh?
驾! 驾! 冲! 宝贝!
Tallyho, Precious!
这匹小马讨厌我
This pony hates me. Oh!
她不是恨你 蒂姆
It's not that she hates you, Tim.
你不配骑马
She just doesn't respect you.
向左!
Go left! Go left!
我只听导航的
I'm gonna go where navigation says.
向左转
Turn left.
谢谢你 导航系统
Thank you, navigation.
啊! 向右转
-Whoa! -Turn right.
对不起
Sorry.
向左转 按当前路线前进
Turn left. Proceed on the current route.
重新规划路线
Recalculating.
抓紧你的东西
Hold on to your holster.
卡罗打来了!
Oh, no. It's Carol!
别接
Don't answer it.
你好 蒂姆
-Hi. -Oh, Tim.
你俩的友谊之旅怎么样?
How's your bonding trip?
嗯…哇!
Uh... Whoa!
慢点
Whoa. Slow down.
你…俩…的…
How... is... your...
友谊之旅咋样?
-bonding trip? -Aah! Whoa.
你在这啊!
You're here!
不 我的意思是…
Oh, no. I mean, um,
我希望你在这里
I wish you were here.
哦,我们也想你
Oh, we miss you, too.
对吧 女孩们?
Don't we, girls?
我们,呃…
We're, uh...
我们要修复兄弟间的关系
We're, uh, rebooting our relationship
就像情同手足 亲密无间的岁月
and, uh, restoring the closeness that we once felt.
太好了 我们得走了
-That's so great. -We've got to go.
你在哪里?
Where are you?
嗯,曲棍球比赛 嘿!
-Uh, a hockey game. -Hey!
他射门 进啦!
He shoots, he scores!
得分啦!
He scores! He scores!
观众们 他得分了!
Ladies and gentlemen, he scores!
-♪抓… -♪捕…
-♪ Busted... -♪ Busted...
-♪开始
-♪ Busted.
那是警笛声吗?
Is that the police?
不是 没有警察
Uh, no, not the police.
你听到的是闹钟声
It's, uh... it's a hockey alarm.
在快点 蒂姆
Faster, Tim.
我才不要回监狱去!
I ain't going back to the clink!
我只是想提醒你们
Now, I just wanted to remind you
塔比莎的表演就在明晚
that Tabitha's pageant is tomorrow night.
你必须在场
You have to be there.
我会以某种形式出现的
Uh, I will be there in one shape or another.
-你承诺吗? -嗯
-You promise? -I promise.
那泰德来吗?
And what about Ted?
节日快乐 警察
Happy holidays, coppers.
你捉不到我的 明白吗?
You're never gonna take me alive, see?
他很忙
Uh, he's busy.
你在干什么?是警察啊
What are you doing? It's the cops.
对不起,警官
Sorry, Officers.
圣诞老人给你们准备了份大礼
Santa's got something for everybody.
对不起
Sorry.
重新规划路线
Recalculating.
这电影如此真实!
Oh, my God! It's so real!
就像身临其境一般!
It's so real! It's so real!
蒂姆?
Tim?
重新规划路线
Recalculating.
向左! 向左!
Left! Left! Left!
重新规划路线
Recalculating.
向右! 向右!
Right, right, right, right, right!
重新规划路线
Recalculating.
我们期待已久的时刻到了!
And now the moment we've all waited for!
按当前路线行走
Proceed on the current route.
看,蒂姆?
See, Tim?
相信…老天爷啊…
Always trust... Holy...
蒂姆?
Tim?
呃,卡罗尔?
Uh, Carol?
你信号不好 我听不见
You're breaking up. I'm losing you.
怎么会 我听得很清楚
No, honey, I can hear you fine.
明晚表演见 有事 挂了 好的
-See you at the pageant. Got to go. Bye. -Okay.
-哇! -对不起
-Whoa! -Sorry.
哦,不,不
Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no.
这票钱太值了!
It's too real! It's too real!
驾! 宝贝!
Tallyho, Precious!
不,不,…哇,哇,!
No, no, no, tally... Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
蒂娜! 蒂娜!
-Tina! -Tina!
哇!
Whoa!
啊!
Woo-hoo!
哇!
Whoa!
树!
Tree!
您已经到达目的地
You've arrived at your destination.
还有一分钟的时间
And with a minute to spare.
哦 嗯
Oh. Huh.
我会赔偿他们的
I'll send them a check.
哦,真有趣
Oh, that was fun.
你做到了
You did it.
我们做到了
We did it.
我想是的
I guess we did.
我刚是对宝贝骏马讲的
I was talking about me and Precious.
哦 是吧 宝贝
-Oh. -Isn't that right, baby?
好吧
Yeah. Right.
趴下!
Get down!
这地方看起来就不对劲
Whoa. This place even looks evil.
这只是一所学校
It's just a school.
你反应过度了
You're overreacting.
"宝宝公司"也是这样
And so is BabyCorp.
我告诉你
No, I'm telling you,
这所学校让塔比莎压力很大
this school is stressing Tabitha out.
塔比莎能搞定
Tabitha can handle it.
虎父无犬子
She's a real chip off the old block.
"虎"是谁? 我啊
-Wait, who's the block? -I'm the block.
我才是女儿的榜样
Well, you can't be the block. I'm the block.
先以身作则吧
Then start acting like a block.
难道我是做的还不够?
Wh-What does that mean? I'm the block.
我永远是楷模 呵 差远了
-I've always been the block. -Yeah. Not even close.
一直言传身教
All I do is block.
起早贪黑 勤勤恳恳
I wake up in the morning, I block.
上行下效
I go to sleep, blocking.
一代楷模 够了
-I'm the block. -Tim, enough.
躬先表率 不,别讲了!
-I'm the block. -No, you're not! Stop it!
嘘
Shh.
太好了
Sweet.
傻缺
Suckers.
由此进入校区 嘿
-Children only beyond this point. -Hey.
请勿在校区内哭泣
No crying is permitted in the separation zone.
看来我们得分头行动了
Okay, looks like we got to split up.
终于不用听你唠叨了
Good. I could use a break.
再见,妈妈 好的,亲爱的
-Bye, Mom. -All right, bye, honey.
塔比莎
There's Tabitha.
放学后见 好的
-I'll see you after school. -Okay.
团队合作
显然,没有A
Apparently, there's no "A"
团队合作
在"团队合作"
in "teamwork," either.
团队合作
快进去吧
All right, let's boogie.
别急
Not so fast.
我是尖子生 你是普通生
I'm blue. You're yellow.
你在那边的小车里集合
You're over there in the choo-choo.
哦 里面全是宝宝
Aw. It's full of babies.
是吗?我没有注意到
Is it? I didn't notice.
真是可笑之极
Just kidding. It's hilarious.
等下 你领带歪了
Uh, wait. Your tie's crooked.
蒂姆 听好了
Okay, Tim, focus.
我们11点15分在博士办公室外见面
We'll meet outside Armstrong's office at 11:15.
我们溜进去,装上窃听器
We'll sneak in, and we'll plant the bugs.
你在听吗?
Are you focused?
你他丫的
Hey, what the...
我目的很明确 不要啊
-Oh, I am focused, all right. -No, no.
我不想去普通班
I'm not yellow. I'm blue.
11:30 准时到
11:30. Stick to the plan.
是11:15
11:15.
明白了 老爸全力以赴
15. Got it. The block is focused.
我是精英啊!
I'm blue! Aah! I'm blue.
弄错了啊 我是尖子生!
Don't you understand? I'm blue!
英语
欢迎
Welcome, children.
德语
欢迎
Willkommen.
法语
欢迎
Bienvenue.
韩语 罗马音
你好
Annyeonghaseyo.
西班牙语
早安
And buenos días.
学院不会辜负你的殷情希望
Thank you for choosing to be excellent.
别碰我
Please don't touch me.
这真荒谬
This is some ridiculous mistake.
我是尖子生!
I'm blue! I'm blue!
汽车轮子的周长是
♪ The wheels on the bus go pi R-squared
-♪ πr   找到了
-♪ Circumference all around. -Yes.
你好
Hello.
嗯,你好
Uh, hello.
漂亮的植物
Nice plant.
这可以提振我的心情
This is my emotional support plant.
嗨 我是新来的
Hi. I-I'm new here.
这就是元素周期表中的其他元素
Said nihonium to the other elements in the periodic table.
哦
Ooh.
好吧
Okay.
不能坐在这里
Can't sit here.
这里没你的位置
Or here. Or there.
座位位置由班级排名决定
Seating position is determined by class rank.
没法根据你的成绩安排座位
We can't possibly include your data,
鉴于你之前学校的教育水平
given that the rigor of your previous school
是一个未知变量
is an unknown variable.
哦
Ooh.
说得好 内森
Sick burn, Nathan.
噢
Ow.
坐这里
Here.
你可以坐我的位子
You can take my seat.
我真为你骄傲
I'm so proud of you.
我的意思是…谢谢
I mean... thanks.
好吧…
Okay...
早上好
Good morning.
早上好,阿姆斯特朗博士!
Good morning, Dr. Armstrong!
谢谢大家
Very warm welcome. Thank you.
嗯?
Huh?
如你所见 有一个新同学
As you can see, we've got a new colleague
刚来我们班上
joining us today.
哦 你好
-Ooh. -Hello.
新同学 自我介绍一下
New colleague, why don't you introduce yourself.
呃 我叫蒂… 马科斯
Uh, my name's Ti... um, Marcos.
光速
Lightspeed
嗯 马科斯莱比
-Hmm. -Marcos Lightspeed.
马科斯莱比
Marcos Lightspeed.
这名字与众不同 有个性 我喜欢
Yeah. Colorful, characterful, and I like it.
不论如何…
In any case...
欢迎来到精英班组
...welcome, Marcos, to Blue Unit.
我们是最先进的班级
Our most advanced class.
我们的竞争
Ooh, this is rarefied air
十分激烈
we're breathing.
在橡子中学,我们相信
Here at The Acorn Center, we believe
所有的竞争都是…
that all competition is...
健康的竞争
Healthy competition.
我被困在"达姆桶"里了
I'm trapped in the dum-dum holding tank.
我恐慌症发作了
I'm having a panic attack.
这里一定有出去的路
There must be a way out of here.
有点不对劲
Something doesn't smell right.
蓝莓味
Blueberry.
我必须离开这里
I have to get out of here.
嗨
Hi.
没见过美女?
Don't look at me.
好吧
Okay.
今天首先要考的是…
And our first subject today is...
别考分数
No fractions, no fractions, no fractions. Whoa!
粒子物理学
Particle physics.
我没听错?
Yes! What?
太好了!
Yes!
谁知道哪个科学家
Who knows which scientist
普朗克尺度
德国物理学家马克斯•普朗克  量子力学创始人之一
1890年提出了一系列的自然单位来简化物理定律
首先提出宇宙有极限的理论
first theorized that the universe has a limit
超出这个范围物理定律就会失效?
beyond which the laws of physics break down?
哇 似乎每个人都知道
Wow. Everybody seems to know.
"光速"先生
Señor Lightspeed.
-33
最基本的普朗克单位分别为长度 质量 温度 时间和电荷
如最小的长度量子 1.6×10    cm
嗯 "诡计"博士吗?
Um, Dr. Flam... baisley?
当这些单位运用到物理定律的时候 物理学家惊奇地发现它们也代表着物理极限
( 这在数学上是完全可行的 但在物理上是不允许的 想象一下超光速的情况发生)
比普朗克还短的距离 更热的温度都是没有任何意义的 也就是说物理定律失效了
回答错误
Oh, that's the wrong answer.
他的大脑肯定不灵光
His brain sure doesn't move at light speed.
哈哈 我知道,对吧?
-Uh, okay. -I know, right?
还有吗? 我知道
-Anybody else? -Right here.
马克斯•普朗克
Max Planck.
回答正确
That's correct.
塔比莎
Tabitha has set the bar.
一马当先 恭喜
First one on the board. Ding, ding, ding.
干得好 塔比莎
Way to go, Tabitha.
你完蛋了 邓普顿
You're going down, Templeton.
放马过来吧
Bring it on, Nathan.
加油 塔比莎 击败他
Yeah, Tabitha. Get him.
下一个考题
Next subject.
古希腊
Ancient Greek.
古希腊戏剧
Ancient Greek Oprah
世界上最古老的戏剧
戏剧!
Opa! Oprah!
注意
Attention.
大家注意
Attention, everyone.
谁想演"肖申克"?
Who wants to play Shawshank?
意指电影"肖申克的救赎" 越狱以重获自由
不! 嗯?
-No! -Huh?
谁想出去玩?
Who wants to go outside and play?
听起来不错吧? 好
Does that sound fun? Good.
有好的主意吗?
Now, anybody have any ideas?
-没! -拜托 大家
-No! -Come on, people.
绞尽脑汁
Think, think, think, think, think.
我们要跳出思维定势
We need to think outside the box.
直译为"跳出盒子思考"
我知道 说
-Oh, oh, oh! Me, me! Oh! -You, Bo-Peep.
我们可以造一个热气球
We can build a hot-air balloon
用冰棒棍和泡泡糖做成!
out of Popsicle sticks and bubble gum!
它怎么飞呢?
And how would it fly?
魔法!
Pixie dust!
对应之前说的"跳出盒子思考"
回盒子里去 波比
Get back in the box, Bo-Peep.
一直进去? 别出来了
-All the way in? -All the way in.
耶! 哦 我们也能进盒子里吗?
-Yay! -Ooh. Uh, can we get in the box, too?
可以吗? 用胶水
-Can we? Can we? -Glue.
我喜欢胶水
I like glue.
谁不喜欢?
Who doesn't?
但我们要集思广益
But we're trying to brainstorm here.
胶水很好
Glue's good.
再想…
Think, think, think, think, think, think...
…快想 快想!
...think, think, think, think, think, think, think, think!
想到啦
Bingo.
下一个考题
Next subject.
此句是在讲解计算过程
X等于导数…
X is equal to the derivative of...
x
导数等于本身的是e
我知道! 它本身
-Ooh, me! -Itself.
厉害 塔比莎
Kudos for Tabitha.
哇 这你都知道?
Wow. You knew that?
世界铝土矿的主要生产商是…
The world's leading producer of bauxite is...
哦! -(在)澳大利亚
-Oh! -Australia.
又一次 塔比莎上荣誉榜
Once again, Tabitha's on the board.
非常好 是的 塔比莎!
-Very good. -Yes, Tabitha!
我们还有15分钟 各位
We got 15 minutes, people.
"尝试"和"成功"的区别
The difference in "try" and "triumph"
就需要股劲头
is just a little oomph.
冲劲! 成王败寇
-Oomph! -Go big or go home.
那我走
Okay. Going home.
加快步伐 抗议!
-Let's pick up the pace. -No!
把牌子放下 这是我的时代
Hand downs, Norma Rae. This is my time.
"生存 还是毁灭?" 塔比莎
To be, or not to be? Tabitha.
威廉·莎士比亚所写 戏剧"哈姆雷特"中的一段独白
默然忍受命运暴虐的毒箭 或是挺身反抗人世无涯的苦难
"斗争" 正确
-To be. -That's correct.
马力 / horsepower
一种计量功率的单位
1马力相当于1匹马所能达到的功率
谁能告诉我302引擎的马力是多少?
Can anyone tell me the horsepower of a 302 engine?
额 7吗?
Uh, seven?
哦 孩子 内森弱爆了
-Oh, boy. -Weak sauce, Nathan.
这都不知道
That was weak.
塔比莎 你知道吗?
Tabitha, do you have an idea about that?
四腔化油器
four-barrel carburetors
又称汽化器 形成可燃混合气的装置
用四腔化油器是300马力
300 horsepower with a four-barrel carb.
哇
Wow.
她爸爸一定是个天才
Her dad must be a genius.
听我的信号 准备
On my signal, unleash heck.
开火!
Fire!
对头!
Yes!
我制出解药了!
I found a cure!
对! 对! 她做到了!
Yes! Yes! She did it!
她做到了
She did it.
马科斯!
Marcos!
我也做到了
I did it. I did it.
记住 聚蚊成雷 众擎易举
Remember, your size doesn't determine your strength.
目前为止 塔比莎名列第一
Well, so far, it's Tabitha number one
其他人
and everybody else last.
嘿 塔比莎
Psst. Hey, Tabitha.
你真的…
You're really...
书呆子 我知道 -不
-A geek. I know. -No.
你真了不起
You're amazing.
哦 谢谢 马科斯
Oh. Thanks, Marcos.
你会在排练表演时失败的
You'll be singing a different tune at rehearsal.
拨乱反正
The wrong tune.
你真有才
You're so funny.
好笑!
Hilarious!
还有 邓普顿 别迟到
And yeah, Templeton, don't be late.
"迟到"
Late.
我迟到了 下一个考题
-I'm late. -Next subject.
终于!
Yes!
再往前一点
Just a little further.
胶水!
Glue!
打扰了
Excuse me.
说 马科斯
Yes, Marcos.
能给我一张通行证吗?我得去
Can I have a hall pass? I have to go.
瞧 随便用
Voilà. Feel free.
现在怎么办呢?
Now what?
胶水!
Glue!
胶水没用!
Glue is bad!
胶水
Glue.
胶水有用!
Glue is good.
怎么去博士办公室
How to get to the principal's office.
对了
Of course.
你会被罚去校长办公室
You get sent to the principal's office.
♪ Booyah!
♪ I think it's very vital to rock a rhyme...
♪ Here we go, it's tricky to rock a rhyme
♪ To rock a rhyme that's right on time, it's tricky
♪ It's tricky, tricky, tricky, tricky
♪ It's tricky to rock a rhyme
♪ To rock a rhyme that's right on time, it's tricky...
咋啦 老铁?
What's up, y'all?
江西老表 东北老铁 山西相好 新疆阿达西
您开心就好
学校真…
School is...
蠢
stupid.
听着 我知道你很厌学
Listen, you know, I acknowledge your anger.
但请不要扰乱课堂秩序
It's, uh, very, uh, feisty, but please sit down.
好吧 哦 不
Okay. Uh, no.
我才不会坐以待毙!
Sitting is... stupid!
他真酷 哦
-He's such a bad boy. -Ooh.
♪ It's tricky to rock a rhyme
♪ To rock a rhyme that's right on time, it's tricky
-♪ How is it, D? -♪ It's tricky, tricky...
好吧 恐怕你不能再扰乱课堂了
All right. I'm afraid you can't disrupt class any longer.
哦 不 我们要去你办公室谈吗?
Oh, no. Are we gonna have a talk in your office?
不
No.
你得"冷静"一下 禁闭屋?
-You are gonna have a time-out. -The Box?
要被关禁闭了
He's going in the Box.
不 那里会让你发疯
No, the Box makes you crazy.
什么东西?
The Box?
♪ Sail away, sail away, sail away
♪ Sail away, sail away
♪ Sail away...
再会,马科斯
Sayonara, Marcos.
"休息"时间
Your time-out begins now.
放松
Relax.
等等!
Wait!
不要哭
Don't cry.
看吧 没事的
There, there. All better.
鲁迅说过
It's like they always
宁可与敌人明打
If you want something done right,
不欲受同人暗算
you have to do it without your brother!
又见面了 "门把手"
We meet again, doorknob.
你好
Hello.
欢迎,欢迎
Welcome, welcome.
法语
请进
Please come in. Entrez vous?
你在这里
You're here.
哦 是的 我…
Oh, yes. I...
正等你呢
I was expecting you.
我…
I...
我以为你
I expected that you
会等着我的 所以
would be expecting me, so there.
对了 我知道你为什么来这
Oh, and, uh, by the way, I know why you're here,
所以 嗯…
so, uh... so there.
你知道?
You do?
嗯哼 当然
Mm-hmm. Yes, I do.
请坐
Have a seat, please.
谢谢你!
Thank you.
你了解自己吗?
You know what you are?
恕我直言 你非常聪明
You are, if I may, extremely intelligent.
继续
Go on.
事实上 我一直在观察你
Uh, as a matter of fact, I've been observing you.
明智地分配时间
Spends time wisely. Check.
充分利用教育资源
Makes good use of classroom materials. Check.
亲历亲为 条件达成
Keeps hands to self. Check.
嘿 忘了"我为人人"吧
Hey, forget "works well with others."
你得让别人为你工作
You make others work well for you.
这正是我准备出版书的名字
That's literally the title of the book I'm working on.
说真的 你不是
No kidding. You had no business
普通班级的学生吧?
being in Yellow Level, did you?
恶意捣乱 完全正确
-It was sabotage. -Sabotage. Exactly.
被嫉妒 恐惧 嘿 我也遇到过
Jealousy, fear. Hey, I faced the same obstacles.
事实上 你让我一见如故
In fact, you know, you remind me a lot of myself
其实 我和你一样
when I was your age,
人小鬼大
which is now.
什么?
What?
想不到吧
Surprise, surprise.
什么?
What the frittata?
好吧
Well put.
你竟然是一个宝宝
He's a ba... You're a baby.
注意 博士是个宝宝
I repeat, you're a baby.
你有那么惊讶吗
So surprised, you said it twice.
(难道你也不懂我)
不幸的是 人们还没准备好…
Unfortunately, people are, uh, not ready for a...
一个身居高位的宝宝
a baby in a position of power.
暂时
Yet.
"大胡子机器"指博士的外壳 伪装
记得给我"大胡子机器"的电话
Remind me to get the number of your muttonchop guy.
我需要你这样的人
You know, I could use somebody like you.
拥有和我一样的高智商
With a superior intelligence like my own.
-真的吗? -嗯
-Uh... really? -Mmm.
一个能…
Somebody who can, uh...
嗯
Mmm.
嗯 是的
Mmm. Yeah.
真正理解我理想的人
Truly comprehend what I'm trying to accomplish.
那人就是我 正确
-Well, you're looking at him. -Bingo.
嗯 我们有个秘密班组
Mmm. We have a secret level.
嗯 为特别的宝宝准备的
Mmm. For very special babies.
嗯 精英中的精英
Mmm. The best of the best.
天才班
Ah. The elite.
比尖子班还好?
Beyond blue?
哦,是的
Oh, yeah. Way beyond.
清华姚班
Way beyond. Ooh.
今天就有堂课
Mmm. There's a meeting today...
…放学后
...after school.
仅限宝宝
Babies only.
我们也许很小 但我们要教成年人
We may be small, but we're about to teach grown-ups
一个大教训
a big lesson.
吃糖吗?
Mmm. Lolly?
好吧
Okay.
下课了
Oh. Time for recess.
再见
Bye-bye.
再见…
Sayonara....
嗯,我觉得很顺利
Well, I think that went well.
你是个宝宝 什么?
-You're a baby. -What?
再说一遍 你个小屁孩
I repeat, you're a baby.
他在说我吗? 最好不是
Is he talking to me? He better not be talking to me,
否则我...阿姆斯特朗?
because I'll... Armstrong?
你说的对 康妮
You're right, Connie.
他说的是邪恶博士
He's talking about Armstrong.
我不知道她怎么了
I don't know what has gotten into her.
但她表现的很怪 费德曼医生
But she's acting strange, Dr. Federman.
是我过于担心了吗?
Isn't it a bit early for terrible twos?
有这种可怕的病吗?
Is there terrible ones? Is that a thing?
这也太幼稚啦
Oh, piano-playing bunny, you slay me.
好啦
Okey dokey.
我们需要有人盯着 录下证据
We need some eyes on the prize, visual confirmation here.
哦 爸爸
Oh, Daddy.
真的好想揍你
If I were there, I'd pinch you so hard.
♪ Sail away, sail away...
你的"禁闭"时间结束了
Your time-out has concluded.
远航? 几点了?
Sail away! What time is it?
休息时间到了
It is time for recess.
我迟到了,我迟到了
I'm late, I'm late, I'm late, I'm late. Come on.
他会理解的 对吧?
He'll understand, right?
好吧 泰德在哪里?
Okay. Where is he? Where is he?
在哪里?嗯…
Where is he? Uh...
得胜 哈哈
Oomph! Yeah, baby!
我的赌注
No, not my bows.
它已经是我的了
But they're not your bows... anymore.
有欺凌 就有泰德
Yep, where there's crying, there's my brother.
嘘 给你
Psst. Here you go.
酷
Cool.
"胶水""胶水"
Glue. Glue. Glue.
这不是精英班的吗 啊!
-Whoa, whoa, whoa. Hey, blue. -Whoa!
这可不是你能来的地方
Where do you think youse going? You lost?
请让我过去好吗?
Could you let me through, please?
不行!
No!
怎么 你在涂色课上挂科了吗?
So, what, did you flunk coloring class, kid?
就这?
Really, guy?
等着
Mmm, cherry.
说啊
Go on.
滚回去
Blues on the other side.
让他过来
Let him through.
好的 没问题
Okay, he's cool.
看到了吗?
See? I'm cool.
我没问题
I'm cool.
你让我失望了 蒂姆
You failed me, Tim.
我当时很无助
I was desperate.
我爬 用胶水做东西
I crawled. I did things with glue
这并不光彩 但我做到了
that I'm not proud of, but I made it.
我一路跑到博士的办公室
I made it all the way to Armstrong's office,
结果蒂姆在哪儿?
and then where's Tim?
抱歉 我… 蒂姆人呢?
-I know. I... -Where's Tim?
我试图… 去哪了? !
-I tried to... -Where's Tim?!
我被关起来了
I was in the Box, okay?
禁闭屋? 禁闭屋?
-The Box? -The Box?
天呐
Glue.
这就对了
Yeah, that's right.
禁闭屋
The Box.
放尊重点
Show a little respect.
这就是我单枪匹马的原因
See, Tim, this is why I work alone.
我定会不负众望
I'll succeed in the mission.
你就负责收拾残局
You can take the pony home.
你唯一做成功的事
The only thing you're ever gonna succeed at
就是孤独终老
is being alone.
恩断 义绝!
-Fine. -Fine!
好啊!
Fine!
我也喜欢小马
I like ponies.
啊! 知道了
Aah! Thank you for sharing.
你搞砸了 邓普顿!
You are blowing it, Templeton!
是的 邓普顿
Yeah, Templeton.
我在努力
I'm trying.
你总是喜欢拖延
Ugh! You always come in a beat late.
对不起 内森 我尽力了
I'm sorry, Nathan. I'm doing my best.
别拖我后腿 我要进茱莉亚音乐学院
Your best is going to keep me out of going to Juilliard.
对 -1 2 3 唱
-Yeah, Templeton. -It's one, two, three
1 2 3 -1 2 3
-and one, two, three. -One, two, three.
1 2 3
And one, two, three
1 2 3 -1 2 3
and one, two, three and one, two, three.
1、2…-快唱啊!
-And one, two... -Oh, come on!
你在逗我吗?
Are you kidding me?
我还需要时间
I just can't do it right now, okay?
我不能 现在不能
I can't. I just can't.
我明天再做 说真的?
-I'll do it tomorrow. -Seriously?
好了好了好了
All right, all right, all right.
明天表演赛见
See you at the pageant tomorrow.
战胜它!
Beat it!
内森 让我来唱吧
Oh, Nathan, Nathan, let me do it.
让我当主唱吧
Let me do it, Nathan.
我想唱这首歌
I want to sing the song.
不
No.
我想看她失败
I want to see her fail.
哦
Oh.
天才
Pure genius.
我等不及了
I can't wait.
我们走着瞧
We'll see about that.
英语
再会 孩子们
Goodbye, children.
再会
Sayonara.
日语 罗马音
再会
Auf Wiedersehen.
德语
再会
Adieu.
法语
西班牙语
再会 孩子们
Adios, niños.
哦 不是吧
Oh, come on.
我的天啊
Oh, my gosh.
停下 听我说
Stop what you're doing.
看 可爱的小马驹
I see a baby pony.
我喜欢小马
I like ponies.
哦 在那!
Oh, over there!
是的!
Yes!
它太可爱了!
It's so cute!
你今天怎么了?
That's it? No hello?
-都没有问候 -什么?
-Not even a "Hi, Mom"? -What?
嗨 塔比莎!
Hi, Tabitha!
哦 嗨
Oh. Hi.
什么?你从没告诉过我
What? You never told me you had
有一个会开车的姐姐
an older sister who could drive.
那是我妈妈
Uh, that's my mom.
塔比莎 让他说完
Tabitha, don't interrupt.
-我是塔比莎的新朋友 -嘿 别闹
-Yeah, I'm a new friend of Tabitha's... -Hey, stop.
哦 真的吗?
Oh, really?
我们才刚认识
I-I mean, we just met.
你叫什么名字?
Well, what's your name, new friend?
停下 你让我难堪
Stop. You're embarrassing me.
马科斯莱比
Marcos. Marcos Lightspeed.
-噢! -蒂娜!
-Ow! -Tina!
发什么疯?
What is with you?
可爱的孩子
Cute kid.
我得回家了 但是走回去的话
Well, I better get going if I'm gonna walk those
离家3.5英里…
three and a half miles home...
还是走雪地…
in the snow...
没有一件夹克
without a jacket.
3英里半?
Three and a half miles?
3.5 6英里 差不多
Three and a half, six--somewhere in there.
那顿晚餐可不会自己加热
Yeah, well, that TV dinner is not gonna microwave itself.
冷冻晚餐/电视晚餐
TV dinner
只需加热即可食用的食物
冷冻晚餐?
TV dinner?
是啊 我是钥匙儿童 没得挑
Yeah, I'm a latchkey kid, so I eat whatever I want.
挂钥匙儿童
latchkey children
脖子上带着钥匙 经常独自在家 无人照顾的孩子
出于安全考虑 外出工作的父母
禁止孩子出去玩 只准在家看电视
"卡通"是我的保姆
Cartoons are my babysitter.
-不 -可怜的我
-No. -Oh, yeah.
♪ Strangers in the night
♪ Exchanging glances
♪ Lovers...
这是什么?
What is this?
是恶作剧吗?
Some kind of prank?
孩子可以如此残忍
Children can be so cruel.
有人吗
Hello.
哇 这简直就是比尔•盖茨的娱乐室…
Whoa. This is exactly like Bill Gates' rec room...
比尔•盖茨
Bill Gates
2020年全球富豪榜第三名 微软公司创始人
但要小一点
but a little smaller.
这里是干什么的?
What is all this?
研究和发展?
Research and development?
产品测试吗?
Product testing?
嗯 直觉告诉我这不是日托所
Huh. Something tells me this isn't day care.
我可以用间谍摄像机了吗
Boy, could I use a spy camera right about now.
♪ Sail away, sail away, sail away.
无论如何…
Anyway...
哦
Aw.
打扮成空手道的你太可爱了
Now, aren't you a cutie in that little karate outfit.
嗯
Huh.
忍者版"后街男孩"吗?
Is this some kind of a ninja boy band?
后街男孩
boyband / Backstreet Boys
顾名思义是由几位男生组成的乐队
哇…!
Whoa...!
哇!
Whoa!
太恐怖了
Oh. Whoa, whoa.
我的天啊 吓死宝宝了!
Oh, my gosh. Oh, my gosh. Oh, my gosh!
哇
Whoa.
我放弃了
I give up.
救命! 救命!
Cobra Kai! Cobra Kai!
再见 宝贝!
Sayonara, baby!
嘿 小伙 哦 你好!
-Hey, there you are. -Oh, hello!
谢谢你!
Thank you.
看来你激怒了忍者宝宝
I see that you've angered my baby ninjas.
哦 不好
Oh, boy. Oh, boy.
走 走
Shoo. Shoo.
哪个地堡会没有忍者把守?
What maniacal underground fortress doesn't have ninjas?
我说的对吧? 厉害吧
-Am I right? -Impressive, huh?
非常令人印象深刻
Pretty impressive.
你觉得呢?你觉得呢?
What do you think? What do you think?
我知道开学校很赚钱
I know tuition is pretty steep,
可建造这些远远不够
but how do you afford all this?
说到点子上啦
Oh, that's a good question.
我教宝宝编程 不会吧
-I taught babies to code. -No.
是的 就如人们常说的
Yes. And you know what they say about having
让无数只猴子敲打字机
an infinite amount of monkeys banging on typewriters?
它们最终会写莎士比亚
They will eventually write Shakespeare?
天啊 你真聪明
A-plus. Oh, boy, you are smart.
或者是最火赚钱的应用
Or the most popular apps that money can buy.
他们正在编写应用程序
Apps. They're writing apps.
"猫聊"
Cat Chat.
"棕树画图"
Palm Doodle.
"找你妹"
Ooh, Find My Nose.
"韭菜收割"
Stock Crush.
这是你做的?
You did Stock Crush?
我喜欢"韭菜收割"
I love Stock Crush.
我的下一个应用…
All us. But my next app...
它会改变世界
ooh, it's gonna change the world.
永远的
Forever.
那为什么要开学校?
So why bother with a school?
你可以上市赚几百万
You could go public and make millions.
哦
Oh.
-数十亿 -数十亿
-Billions. -Billions.
是啊 但有些东西比钱更重要
Yeah, but some things are more important than money.
请不要说"爱"
Please don't say "love."
嗯 权力
Mmm. Power.
这才是实话
That's more like it.
哇 这太棒了
Wow. This is so amazing.
先是搭车 又是蹭饭
First, the ride, and now a-a full sit-down dinner.
正式晚餐
Sit-down Dinner
也叫晚宴 社交聚会
哇 装修的真好
Wow. What a palace.
你们居然付得起电费? 是的
-I mean, you have electricity? -Well, yeah.
伙计 你们太慷慨了
Man, you guys are beyond generous.
随时欢迎你
You're welcome anytime.
塔比莎 你能不能
Tabitha, would you mind
-布置下餐桌 -好的 妈妈
-setting the table? -Okay, Mom.
你就这样乱放东西?
Really? You're just gonna throw that right there, huh?
嘿 爸爸
Psst. Psst. Daddy.
-嘘!叫我马科斯 -你来干什么?
-Shh! It's Marcos. -What are you doing here?
-泰德叔叔呢? -什么?
-Where's Uncle Ted? -What?
他把我从任务除名了
He kicked me off the mission.
他无权那么做
He can't do that.
只有我才行
Only I can do that.
你回来执行任务了
You're back on the mission.
不用 我现在有自己的任务
No need. I have my own mission now.
还有什么比我的任务更重要?
What? What could be more important than my mission?
"光速"闪啦
Got to go. Lightspeed out.
这太棒了
This is so great.
希望你能多吃点
Well, I hope you're hungry.
我很久没用银器了
Been so long since I've used silverware.
来新学校第一天感觉如何?
So, how'd you like your first day?
氛围有点紧张
Kind of intense.
对 你会习惯的
Yeah. You'll get used to it.
我永远无法接受内森 内森
-Even that Nathan kid? -Nathan.
他无可救药了 是啊
-Ugh. He's a mess -Yeah.
他真是个古板的人 广场?
-He is such a square. -A square?
是啊 你懂的 太装逼了
Uh, yeah, you know, like a dork.
自以为是 目中无人 书呆子
Dweeb. Nerdlet. A real poindexter.
无聊透顶 笨蛋
Lame-o. Dorkus to the max.
以前也有人这么叫我
They used to call me.
-你好怪 -是吗?
-You're weird. -I am?
我是在夸你 没恶意
Yeah, but in a good way.
为什么表演赛让你如此紧张?
So, why is the pageant stressing you out so much?
我要唱歌
I have to sing.
这没啥啊? 我也说不清
-So what? -I don't know.
全家都会去看
My whole family is going to be there,
包括我爸爸
including my dad.
哦
Oh.
对啊
Right.
你觉得他会让你难堪?
You're embarrassed of him?
不 不是
No. No, it's not that.
只是他真的很擅长这种事
It's just, he's really good at this kind of thing--
发挥创造力和想象力
being creative and using your imagination--
我却很难做到
but it's hard for me.
我只是想让他引以为傲
I just want him to be proud of me.
你懂吗?
You know?
真的吗?
Really?
嗯 是的
Well, yeah.
这些多余的餐盘是给谁准备的?
Um, who are these extra plates for?
妈妈和爸爸
Mom and Dad.
嘿! "钥匙"还能用!
Hey, hey! The key still works!
你们真该换把锁了
You guys should really change the locks.
你们来了 爷爷来啦
-Oh, you made it. -Look who's here!
妈妈和爸爸
Mom and Dad.
奶奶!爷爷!
Grandma! Grandpa!
我的乖孙女
There she is.
过来抱抱 我的小宝贝 耶!你来了!
-Come here, my little tabby cat. -Yay! You're here!
长大啦不少 你都快成青少年
-Look at how big you are. -You're almost a teenager.
(你多大了)
你有选举权了吗?
Can you vote yet?
奶奶我10岁半啦
Ten and a half more years, Grandma.
爸爸 他们会认出你的
Daddy, they're gonna recognize you.
不 没事
No, no. It's fine.
我有眼镜作伪装
I've got the glasses. See?
自拍! 你是怎么做到的?
-and Selfie! -How do you do it again?
小宝宝呢
Bring out the baby.
我躲! 你把宝宝藏哪儿了?
-Hide! -Where are you hiding that baby?
别慌 镇定点
No. Just be cool. Be cool.
-她在这 -嗨
-There she is. -Hello.
嘿 这陌生小伙是谁?
Hey, who's the new guy?
是马科斯 我明白了
-That's Marcos. -I gotcha.
注意 宝宝
Attention, babies.
法语
欢迎
Bienvenue.
德语
欢迎
Willkommen.
俄语
欢迎
Dobro pozhalovat.
合十礼
And namaste.
泰语 亦表欢迎
哦,孩子
Uh, babies.
嘿 嘿
Hey, hey.
别再看屏幕了
No more screen time.
听好了
Listen.
信不信由你 我以前和你们一样
Believe it or not, I used to be just like you.
我的父母
Yes. I even had parents.
是儿童心理学家
Mine were child psychologists
拿我做实验
who made me part of an experiment.
真的吗?
Really?
让我暴露在上万小时的环境中
They exposed me to 10,000 hours
小提琴练习 语言课程和广播电台学习
of Mozart, language lessons and public radio.
我讨厌听广播
I hate public radio.
就在那时 我意识到我比父母更聪明
It was at that point I realized I was smarter than my parents.
我的第一步 离家出走
And with my first step, I ran away from home.
为什么?
Why?
我要脱离他们的掌控
They pushed me around.
独立自主 掌控自己的未来
I got told what to do all the time.
一个字就可改变你我的生活
But a single word changed my life.
"不" 说出来
"No." Say it.
不!
No!
打个盹 不!
-Take a nap. -Nyet!
穿上你的外套 不行!
-Put on your coat. -Nein!
多吃蔬菜 不!
-Eat your vegetables. -Nahii!
你想让家长们摆布你吗?
Are you gonna let grown-ups push you around?
不 不! 不想!
No, no! No, no, no! No, no! No, no, no!
你想吗? 幸好没有
-Are you? -Good God, no.
要勇于抗争
That's right.
凭什么成年人是掌权者?
Why do parents get to be in charge, anyway?
他们把社会治理成啥样了?
They had their chance, and what did we get?
环境恶化 政局动荡 战争频发
Pollution, politics, wars.
哦
Ooh.
不要"哦" 要"嘘"
Not "ooh." "Boo."
嘘!
Boo!
成年人是我们成功路上的绊脚石
The only thing holding us back is them,
情况要改变了
but not anymore.
我们努力奋斗的时刻就要到来了
The moment that we've worked so hard for is almost here.
此处命名是仿照 D-day
诺曼底登陆战役的行动日期
"革命日"
B-Day.
什么? "革命日"
-B-Day? -B-Day.
我3岁啦 我也是
-I'm this many. -I'm this many.
BDAY / b-day
是birthday(生日)的缩略写法
不是…今天不是你的生日
No, no, it's not... it's not your birthday.
这是宝宝革命的开始
It's the beginning of the baby revolution.
耶,耶
Yay, yay.
还有蛋糕 蛋糕
And there'll be cake. Cake for everybody.
蛋糕!蛋糕!蛋糕!
Cake! Cake! Cake! Cake! Cake! Cake!
没有规则
No more rules.
哦啦啦!
Oh là là!
没有父母
No more parents.
哦
Uh-oh.
再见 妈妈和爸爸!
Sayonara, Mama and Papa!
哦 这太糟了
Oh, this is bad.
好了 动员会结束
All right, pep rally's over.
你们父母会来接你们
Your-your parents are gonna pick you up.
这是我毕生的心血
This is my life's work.
是的 长达17个月
Oh, yes, 17 long months.
敬没有父母
To... no more parents.
嗯
Mmm.
为革命干杯
Cheers to the revolution.
不 不 不
No. Nope. Nope.
不 哦 这张拍的不错 蒂娜
-No. Oh, that's a keeper. -Oh, Tina.
哦 太可爱了 这个应用叫什么?
Oh, it's so cute. What's the app called?
叫"美图捕捉" 哦
-It's called QT Snap. -Oh.
告诉我怎么下载 每个人都有
-Show me how to download that. -Everyone has it.
所以,马科斯…"光速"?
So, Marcos... Lightspeed?
你叫这名字? 嗯
-Is that what you said? -Mm-hmm.
听起来像个卡通名字
Sounds like a cartoon name.
它确实
It really does.
我的父母 他们有点古怪 所以…
Well, my parents, they're a little wacky, so...
嗯 我好像在什么地方见过你
Huh. It's like I know you from somewhere.
不可能
I don't think so.
这张也可以留下 嘿 嘿
-That is a keeper, too. -Hey. Hey.
-他看起来面熟吗?-我不知道
-Doesn't he look familiar? -I don't think I do.
对啊 他长得很像蒂姆
Yeah, he looks just like Tim.
是的 你看起来像蒂姆
Yeah. You look like Tim.
嗯? 嗯?
-Hmm? -Huh?
除了蒂姆没有戴眼镜
Except Tim didn't wear glasses.
哦 是啊
Oh, that's right.
嗯 无法反驳把
Huh. Well, how about that.
嘿 蒂姆去哪了?
Hey, where is Tim, anyway?
蒂姆和泰德在旅行
Tim and Ted are on a trip.
一起? 他们现在很要好
-and Together? -They're bonding.
终于和好了 是的
-Well, that's about time. -Yeah.
我只希望蒂姆能及时回来看表演
I just hope Tim's back in time for the pageant.
哦,为什么…他为什么不会来呢?
Uh, why... why wouldn't he be there?
蒂姆 拖延症
-Tim Time. -Tim Time.
哦
Oh.
什么是"蒂姆时间"?
What's-what's Tim Time?
说吧 好的
-Go ahead. -Okay.
马科斯 蒂姆时间就像个黑洞
Well, Marcos, Tim Time is like a black hole
在现实和准时等方面迷失了方向
where things like reality and being on time get lost.
哦
Oh.
塔比莎的父亲想象力很丰富
Tabitha's father has a very active imagination.
这是一件好事
Which is a good thing.
对…我得说这是件好事
Yeah, that's a... I'd say that's a good thing.
还记得他说"老板"想绑架我们吗?
Oh, remember when he said our boss was trying to kidnap us?
他说过?
He did?
或者泰德是婴儿时会走路说话
Or that his baby brother could walk and talk
但只在我们不注意的时候
but only when we weren't looking.
哇 转身看啊
Wow. Turn around.
太像爸爸了
That's so Dad.
泰德也挺难对付的
You know, Ted was quite a handful himself.
-哦 他可能很… -焦虑
-Oh, he could be very... -Uptight.
是的 神经紧张
Mm. Yes. High-strung.
哦 还记得他起诉我们那次吗?
Oh. Remember the time he sued us?
青少年啊
Teenagers. Ugh.
不过他真的很尊敬他哥哥
He really looked up to his big brother, though.
是吗? 是的
-He did? -Oh, yeah.
他天天粘着他哥哥
He wouldn't leave him alone.
蒂姆做的每件事 泰迪都想做
Everything Tim did, Teddy wanted to do.
真的? 是的
-Really? -Yeah.
我们叫他跟屁虫泰迪
Tagalong Teddy, we called him.
这可不能让他听到 对
-Well, not to his face. -No, no.
不会当面叫 他很爱较真
Not to his face. He was very litigious.
但你爸爸并不介意泰德
But you know what? Your dad didn't mind.
他为泰德感到自豪
He was so proud of his little brother.
哦 是的 他喜欢炫耀他
-Oh, yeah. -He loved showing him off.
那俩兄弟做什么都在一起
Those guys did everything together.
兄弟情深
They were best friends.
就像你和我
Just like you and me.
蒂娜?
Right, Tina?
永远好的朋友
Best friends forever.
挠痒痒!
Tickle monster!
真幸福
That's so sweet.
这是我的壁橱
And this is my closet.
-哦,很酷的壁橱里 -这是我的床
-Oh, cool closet. -And this is my bed.
这是我的鱼
And this is my fish.
嘿 想看非常酷的东西吗? 当然
-Hey, want to see something really, really cool? -Sure.
我为霍金医生做了这个发声器
I made this vocalizer for Dr. Hawking.
嗨,我的老…
Hey, my old...
你干了什么? 看这个
-What did you do?! -Check this out.
打个招呼吧 霍金博士
Say hello, Dr. Hawking.
你…
Hell-l-l-l-l...
他看到陌生人讲不出话
Um, he has performance anxiety.
嗯哼 是的
Mm-hmm. Yep.
哦 这是"咩咩"
Oh, this is Lamb Lamb.
嘿 "咩咩"
Hey, Lamb Lamb.
架子上是我的星系模型
That's my galaxy model right up there on my shelf.
我的科学周嘉奖
My scientist of the week award.
哇 我的晶洞石收藏
-Wow. -My geode rock collection.
我的望远镜
And my telescope.
不错
Sweet.
-吉他不错 -是的
-Hey, cool guitar. -Yeah.
是我爸爸的
That's my dad's.
酷爸爸
Cool dad.
你还好吗?
Are you okay?
是啊 我好像长高了
Yeah, I'm a lot taller in my mind.
我可以弹吉他给你唱歌伴奏
Hey, if you want, I can help you with your song.
不
No, you can't.
我歌声很刺耳的 别拘束啦
-Your ears will bleed. -Oh, please.
会很好玩的
It'll be fun.
这首怎么样? 经典曲目
How about this one? It's a classic.
一定要唱吗?
Do we have to?
来吧 试一试
Come on. Let's try.
好吧
Okay.
不过别太乐观
It's not gonna be good, though.
我不评断
No judgment.
我们只是在找乐子
We're just having fun.
♪ There's no place like home
♪ For the holidays
别唱了
Please stop.
♪ 'Cause no matter
不 快停下!
No, stop. Aah...!
♪ How far away you roam...
不…错
Good... try.
我太紧张了
Ugh! I just get so nervous.
没关系
That's okay.
听着 你要做的是
Listen, all you got to do
用心去感受歌曲
is imagine that you're inside the song.
体会歌词的意境
Everything in the lyrics is actually happening to you.
随之高声歌唱
And you can see the notes.
♪ Well, if you want to sing out, sing out
♪ And if you want to be free, be free
♪ 'Cause there's a million things to be
♪ You know that there are
哇 马科斯,等等
Whoa. Marcos, wait up.
来吧
Come on.
♪ And if you want to sing high, sing high
♪ And if you want
太高了
That's a little too high.
♪ To sing low, sing low
抓住你啦
I got you.
♪ 'Cause there's a million ways to go
♪ You know that there are
我的天,那太多了
OMG, that's a lot.
♪ Uh-huh, it's easy
♪ Uh-huh
♪ You only need to try
♪ You can sing what you want
哇!是的,这很有趣!
Whoo! Yeah, this is fun!
♪ The opportunity's yours
♪ And if you do it your way
哇
Whoa.
♪ You can do it today
马科斯,等等 你在哪里?
Marcos, wait. Where are you?
来吧 你可以的
Come on. You can do it.
我不能 我不能
I can't. I can't.
现在开始吧
Now go for it.
♪ Ah-ah-ah
哇
Whoa.
嘿
Hey.
♪ It's easy
♪ Ah-ah-ah
♪ You only need to try
好吧 轮到我了
All right. My turn.
开始吧 尽情唱
Here we go. It's all you.
♪ Well, if I want to sing out, sing out
♪ Sing out
对 唱出来
Yes, let it out.
♪ And if I want to be free, be free
♪ Be free
♪ 'Cause there's a million things to be
♪ I know that there are, I know that there are
-♪ I know that there are -♪ You know that there are
-♪ I know that there are... -♪ You know that there are...
♪ I know that there are.
唱出来的感觉太爽啦
Wow. That was so great.
你唱的很好
No, you were so great.
谢谢 马科斯
Thanks, Marcos.
什么?
What?
哦 值得纪念的一刻 动静小点
-Oh, that's a keeper. -Oh, they can see us.
他们能看见我们 哦
-They can see us. -Aw.
大伙 来吧
Guys, come on.
别 别这样做
Stop. No, do it. Do it.
哦 不
Oh, no.
父母恩勤
Parents, right?
再见 邓普顿一家! 再见
-Bye, Templeton family! -Bye-bye.
再见 马科斯"光速"
-Bye, Marcos. -Lightspeed.
奇怪的孩子
Weird kid.
是的 我不喜欢他
Yeah, I don't like him.
♪ Catch my eye
♪ Take my hand
♪ This bond is tighter than we
搞定他们 塔比莎
You go get 'em, Tabitha.
♪ Ever planned
♪ Give me courage
♪ So I can land...
快接 快接
Pick up, pick up, pick up, pick up,
接电话啊
pick up, pick up, pick up, pick up, pick up,
急死我啦
pick up, pick up, pick up, pick up. Choo-choo!
难道不知道情况十分危机吗?
Don't they understand it's the fate of the world?
一直让我等着
I've been on hold forever!
所有的接线员都在打盹
All operators are currently napping.
等到我牙都长出来了
I've been on hold so long I got a tooth growing in.
在我那个年代 都是写备忘录
Back in my day, we wrote memos.
不错 老古董
That's cute and old-timey.
年轻人真弱
I weep for the future.
你想和我谈谈心吗?
Do you want to talk about your feelings now while I'm on hold?
我可以给你20分钟
I can give you 20 minutes.
不
No.
让我们直蹦主题吧
Let's get to the nut, the nugget.
你在害怕什么?
What are you afraid of?
鲨鱼 被箭射中头部
Sharks, getting shot in the head with an arrow,
和…美国国税局
and... the IRS.
就这些 看吧
-That's it. -There you go.
有那么难吗? 一步步来
Was that so hard? Baby steps.
那么 孤独呢?
Now, what about being lonely?
我不孤独 嗯
-I'm not lonely. -Mm-hmm.
我习惯独处
I'm just... alone.
这是有区别的
There's a difference.
你该看看你的档案
I think it's time you read your file.
给我
Just give me.
哇 这就是?
Whoa. This is it?
也太薄了
It's so thin.
敬爱的宝贝老板
Dear Boss Baby,
我向你保证
I promise you
每天早上你醒来的时候 我都会在你身边
Every morning when you wake up, I will be there.
每天晚饭的时候 我都会在
Every night at dinner, I will be there.
每个生日派对 每个圣诞节早晨
Every birthday party, every Christmas morning,
我都会陪伴你
I will be there.
年复一年
Year after year after year.
你和我是永远的兄弟
And you and I will always be brothers.
永远
Always.
为你俩感到抱歉
Makes me want to make a sad face.
我们只是孩子
We were just kids.
我们对现实世界一无所知
We didn't know anything about the real world.
最终 你得长大
And eventually, you have to grow up.
长大并不意味着
Just because you grow up, it doesn't mean
你们必须分开
you have to grow apart.
也许已经无法挽回了
I don't know. Maybe it's already too late.
嘿
Hey.
对不起 我迟到了
Sorry I'm late.
爸爸!
Daddy!
爸爸 爸爸
Daddy, Daddy.
发生了什么?
What's going on?
泰德叔叔真的很想你
Uncle Ted really misses you.
是不是很好?
Isn't that nice?
嘿 你在干嘛?
So, hey, uh, what you doing?
哦 我在…
Oh, I was, uh...
没什么 我只是在研究这个
I don't know, I was just working on this.
我很抱歉 在操场说了那些话
Look, I'm sorry about what I said at recess.
这句话改编自美国谚语
发生在拉斯维加斯的事 就留在拉斯维加斯吧
what happens in vegas stays in vegas
时过境迁 既往不咎
What happens on the playground stays on the playground.
我当时口不择言
I was just worried about Tabitha, you know?
爱子心切 我懂
She's your daughter. I get it.
我总是以己度人
This whole time, I was thinking about
而不考虑女儿的诉求
what I wanted and not what she needed.
我终于明白了这个育人的道理
I think I finally got this parenting thing figured out.
给你满分 爸爸
Gold star for you, Daddy.
再接再厉 老爸 还有件事
-Keep it up, Pops. -Yeah, well, about that.
博士想对成年人 家长下手
Armstrong wants to get rid of parents somehow.
什么? 他在计划一场宝宝革命
-Sorry, what? -He's planning a baby revolution.
就不能消停会吗
Ugh, come on.
偏偏在我刚擅长做父母时发生
Just when I got good at this whole parenting thing.
我们得阻止他
We got to stop him.
不是我们 就你一个?
-Not we. -You?
我俩都不是
Neither one of us.
"宝宝公司"接手 啊
-BabyCorp is taking it from here. -Ah.
他们要派"宝宝"特种兵来吗?
So, what, they're gonna send in the Baby SEALS or something?
美国"海豹"特种部队
UnitedStatesNavySea,AirandLand，SEAL
直属美国海军的一支特种部队
大概吧 所以你…
-Looks like it. -So you'll, um...
你会直奔办公室处理公务
you'll be headed back to your office.
是的 保持联系 蒂姆
Uh, yeah. Well, keep in touch, Tim.
喂 "宝宝公司"
Hello? BabyCorp?
谢天谢地 终于接通啦…
Thank goodness, BabyCorp. Well, BabyCo...
你在说什么
Wha-What? What are you saying,
没有足够的证据吗?我…
there's not enough evidence, BabyCorp? I...
所以你不打算采取行动?
So you're not gonna do anything?
但是 我…
But, BabyCorp, I...
既然如此那我们来处理
Ugh. Well, then we'll take care of it.
宝宝公司
You know what, BabyCorp?
我不干了!
I quit!
真是群酒囊饭袋
What a bunch of diaper sniffers.
看来得靠自己阻止博士了
Looks like we have to stop Armstrong ourselves.
破坏阴谋 我喜欢
We're going rogue. I like it.
任务又开始了? 是的
-So the mission's back on? -Yeah.
前提是你俩能再容忍一下对方
If you two can put up with each other a little longer.
我想我可以 蒂姆你呢?
I suppose I can live with that. Tim?
我也觉得可行
I think that's doable.
耶!
Yay!
"被迫"组团合作
Forced together again.
现在是8点45分
It's 8:45 p.m.
我们的时间紧迫
Okay. Our clock is ticking.
我们得在"变身"奶粉失效前阻止博士
We have to stop Armstrong before the formula wears off.
齐心协力 我们将在表演赛上开始行动
Working as a team, we will strike at the pageant.
开始吧 蒂娜
Go, Tina.
这份绝密"文件"…
Now, this top secret document...
亲爱的 是绝密"计划"
Sweetie, it's the program.
这个绝密计划揭示了
This top secret program reveals
博士计划向观众发表演讲
that Armstrong is scheduled to address the audience,
他会在表演结束时攻击
which he will do right here at the very end.
蒂姆 我们需要你在后台
We need someone backstage. Tim, that's you.
我都不表演 怎么混进后台?
How am I gonna get backstage if I'm not in the pageant?
我的人会解决的
My people will take care of that.
啊! 谢谢
-Ah! -Thank you.
谢谢你!
Thank you.
不! 太好了
-No! -Great.
去…吧
And... go.
"粘上"
Glue.
别动 马上就好
There, there. All better.
太棒了
Awesome.
而我混在听众中 观察动向 传递情报
Now, I'll be your eyes and your ears in the audience.
不能让妈妈发现我会讲话
I can't let Mommy see me talk,
否则她会尖叫着拥抱我
or she's gonna start squealing and hugging me,
但这些小玩意儿能让你
but these little doodads will let you
听懂我的"儿语"
understand my baby talk.
它被称为"嘎嘎"设备
It's called a GAGA device.
真机灵 试一试
-Aw, that's cute. -Check it out.
爸爸 你能听懂吗?
Can you hear me, Daddy?
很精巧
Also cute.
与此同时 有我做内应
Meanwhile, with my new purple status,
我可以待在博士身边
I can stay close to Armstrong.
嗯 那是眉毛
Um, that's-that's an eyebrow.
哦 对不起 呃,不,那是,呃…
-Oh. Sorry. -Uh, no, that's, uh...
当时机成熟
When the moment is right,
我会植入一个装置
I'll implant a device.
搞定 忘记什么?
-Got it. -Got what?
我是说 你可以的
I mean, you've got this.
去征服他们
Go get 'em, tiger.
哦 谢谢你们大家
Oh, thank you, parents.
谢谢!
Thank you. There's the...
谢谢大家一如既往的支持
There's the old enthusiasm I like to see.
这样我就能控制他的战衣了
This will allow me to control his suit.
通过平板操纵"大胡子机器"
I can make Muttonchops do whatever I want.
可以让他跳舞
I can make him dance.
能使他腾跃
I can make him prance.
嘿 不 不 展现秘密
-Hey, no, no, no, no. -Including exposing himself
给观众知道
to the audience.
每个家长都会拍下这一幕
Every parent will pull out their phone.
别拍 别拍我!
Don't look at me. Don't look at me!
照片会像尿布疹一样扩散
The photos will spread like a diaper rash.
之后是欢庆披萨派对
Cut to our pizza party.
有问题吗?
Questions?
在塔比莎唱完之后开始?
After Tabitha sings her solo, right?
对
After Tabitha sings.
现在我们只用等待表演
Now we just sit back, relax and enjoy the show.
家长们 欢迎来到学校的节日庆典
Welcome, parents, to our holiday pageant.
记住 在礼堂里用闪光灯拍照
Remember, flash photography in the auditorium
效果才是最好的
is absolutely okay.
录下孩子的精彩时刻 表达你的爱意
Take a picture. Show your kids that you love 'em.
好啊!
Yippee!
蒂姆快来啊
Come on, Tim.
你承诺过会来的
You promised you'd be here.
对不起 这个座位有人坐了
Oh, sorry. This seat is taken.
对不起 哦 不
-Yep. Sorry. -Oh, no.
抱歉 我…对不起
So sorry. I... Sorry.
对不起! 我很抱歉
Sorry! I am so sorry.
泰迪叔叔 你就位了吗?
Uncle Teddy, are you in position?
宝宝在摇篮里
The baby's in the cradle.
-目标已就位 -嗯
-The baby's in the cradle. -Mmm.
熊爸爸 你能听到吗?
Papa Bear, can you read me?
雪花落下来了
The flake has landed.
就位! 大家就位!
Places! Places, everybody!
表演开始 哦 我的天啊
-Here we go. Here we go. -Oh, my gosh.
终于开始了
It's starting. It's starting. Finally.
开始啦
It's starting. It's starting.
耶!
Yay!
你喜欢看表演? 不 不
-You're a big pageant guy, huh? -No, no, no.
我不是在说节目 我说的是计划开始
I'm not talking about the show. I'm talking about B-Day.
"革命日"?
B-Day?
已经在父母的手机里开始了
Oh, yeah. It's already in the parents' phones.
我教宝宝编程
I taught babies to code.
他们正在编写应用程序
Apps. They're writing apps.
但我的下一个应用…
But my next app...
它会永远改变世界的
ooh, it's gonna change the world forever.
"美图捕捉"是一个革命性的应用程序吗?
QT Snap is the app that's going to change the world forever?
永远从今天开始
Forever starts today.
额不错
Uh, cool.
哦
Aw.
♪ It's wintertime
♪ It's the best time of year
♪ But due to ice caps melting
♪ Global warming's here
♪ It feels like summer
♪ The snow has disappeared
♪ It's all our parents' fault
-♪ So we're all doomed -All, uh...
♪ Doomed.
这有点暗
This is kind of dark.
歌词说我们完蛋了?
Did the kids just say we're doomed?
这节目真无厘头
What the heck are we watching?
这编剧脑子坏了吧?
Their brains are turning to mush.
几个月的研究 将催眠嵌入应用
Months of hypnotic research embedded
有史以来最好的照片美化应用
in the most user-friendly photo app ever made.
哦
Ooh.
现在要做的就是静观其变
Now all we need to do is sit back, relax
享受表演吧
and enjoy the show.
嘿! 对
-Hey! -Right.
我马上回来  呃…我
I'll be right back. We're, uh...
嘿! 再拿点零食来
-Hey! -...out of Dundle Floofers.
嗯
Mmm.
排灯节!
Diwali!
印度宗教秋季节日
拉斯波萨达斯!
Las Posadas!
美国冬季节日 做祈祷和唱颂歌
不可知论!
Agnostic!
引申为无信仰者
和光明节!
And Hanukkah!
犹太教节日 纪念夺回耶路撒冷
你儿子很有天赋
Your son is so talented.
你儿子也是 说谎
-Oh, so is yours. -Liars.
蒂娜 "革命日"行动已经开始了
Tina, come in. B-Day is happening now.
阴谋都在手机里
It's all in the phones.
博士在用一款应用给父母洗脑
Armstrong is using an app to brainwash the parents.
不好
Gasp.
我们必须停止表演
We have to stop the show.
好吧 嗯 有一个…
Okay, okay. Uh, there's a...
后台有个老式的电源开关
there's a big old no-touchy switch backstage.
爸爸 我们得拔掉插头
Daddy, we have to pull the plug.
爸爸 加入谈话啊
Daddy, come in. Daddy, Daddy, Daddy, Daddy,
爸爸 回过神来 别看了
Daddy, Daddy, Daddy, Daddy, Daddy, Daddy.
啊 他没有回应
Ugh. He's not responding.
不愧是他
Of course not.
我自己来 停下!
-I'll do it myself. -Stop!
表演者才能上台
Theater kids only.
耶稣降生
the Nativity
正在上演基督降生记这个家喻户晓的故事
拜托 把耶稣降生!
Oh, come on, nativity!
弄得再神圣点!
Look holier!
嘿,塔比莎
Hey, Tabitha.
别担心 好吗?
Don't you worry, okay?
你会成功的
You're gonna be great.
马科斯 谢谢你的鼓励
Thanks, Marcos. And thanks for all your help.
我永远支持你
Anytime.
我觉得你真的很懂我
I feel like you really understand me.
我很期待看到
I'm so excited.
爸爸因为我唱歌而引以为豪
I can't wait to see the look on my dad's face when I sing.
邓普顿! 你在这
Hey! You're on, Templeton!
祝我好运吧
Wish me luck.
大获成功
And break a leg.
团队荣耀
Or two, for that matter.
♪ We're in this together
♪ We live in harmony...
嘘
Psst.
蒂姆!
Tim!
那是小耶稣吗?
Is that the baby Jesus?
我们必须停止表演赛
♪ We have to shut down the pageant.
什么? 为什么?
Yeah! What? No. Why?
博士正在控制家长们的大脑
Armstrong's turning the parents into zombies
让他们变成行尸走肉
so they'll do whatever he wants.
你在干什么? 不!
What? What are you doing? No!
塔比莎马上要表演啦
Tabitha's on next.
你会拿世界的未来冒险
You'd risk the future of the world
-去看你女儿唱歌? -是的!
-to see your daughter sing? -Yes!
-我必须完成承诺 -看看谁
-I have to be there for her. -Look who's worried about
突然关心起这个啦
showing up for things all of a sudden.
这话什么意思?
What's that supposed to mean?
你都没来参加我的毕业典礼
You didn't even come to my graduation.
哪一个?
Ow! Which one?
商学院 法学院 就都没来
Business school, law school. None of them.
你也没来参加我的婚礼
You didn't even come to my wedding.
哪一次? 我只有一次!
-Which one? -I only had one!
我们说好了的 蒂姆
We had a deal, Tim.
你说过会一直陪着我的
You promised you'd be there always.
毕业时 你在哪…
Whoa. Where did you...
违反合同!
Breach of contract!
哇
Whoa.
啊! 啊!
-Whoa! -Whoa!
你们好吗 伙计们?
How do you do there, fellas?
没什么能毁了我的计划
Nothing's gonna ruin my B-Day.
即使是你
Not even you.
被逮到了 是的 很明显
-Oh, busted. -Yeah, it was obvious
从最开始
from the very, very beginning
你俩在一起工作
that you two were working together.
是什么露出了端倪?
What gave us away?
我想说的是争吵
Well, I'd say the bickering,
那些小纠纷
the, uh, petty disputes,
嫉妒
the jealousy.
知道吗 你俩很相像
You know, you two are brothers in every single way.
送他们去禁闭
Off to the Box they go.
不 别是现在
What? No. Not the Box. Not now.
求你了
Please.
真可惜你永远没有机会
Aw, it's just... it's too bad that you're never gonna
重新开始你和兄弟的关系…
have a chance to reboot your relationship and...
不! 修复曾经的兄弟情
-No! -...and restore the closeness
你曾有过的感觉
that you once felt.
抱歉 不
-Sorry about that. -No.
不  不! 再见 马科斯
-No, no, no, no. No! -Adios, Marcos.
♪ Ooh-ooh-ooh-ooh...
哦 看 她就在那儿
Oh, look, look. There she is.
我们的小天使来了
There's our little angel.
哦!斑猫在树上 啊!哦!
-Oh! Tabby's in the tree. -Ah! Oh!
♪ Ooh-ooh, ooh-ooh
♪ Ooh-ooh-ooh...
你只有一个任务要做
You had one job to do.
你还搞砸了
One job.
哦 不 喷水了
-Oh, no. -The fountain.
房间里都是水
It's flooding the room.
这不是暂停
This isn't a time-out.
这是游戏结束
It's game over.
♪ Ooh-ooh
♪ Ooh-ooh-ooh
嘘
Psst.
1 2 3 唱 1 2 3 唱
It's one, two, three and one, two, three.
♪ Catch my eye
♪ Take my hand
♪ This bond is tighter than we ever planned
♪ Give me courage
♪ So I can land
♪ We know that divided we'll fall
♪ So together we stand
♪ Laugh and cry with me
♪ Fly that high with me
♪ See the sunset and the sunrise
♪ The world looks so good through our eyes -Wow.
♪ Like the moon and stars at night
你是对的 我搞砸了
You're right. I blew it.
我毁了这次任务
I ruined the mission.
我是个糟糕的父亲
And I'm a terrible father.
你确实破坏了这次任务
Hey, you did sort of ruin the mission.
但你是个好爸爸
But you're a great dad.
不 我不是
No, I'm not.
我永远做不到你那样
I could never do your job.
日以继夜地照顾家人
I mean, you work around the clock,
想辞职都不能
you can't even quit if you wanted to,
连工资都拿不到
and you don't even get paid.
坦白说 我不明白这合理吗
Frankly, I don't see how that's legal.
我一直很嫉妒你
I was always jealous of you.
我也想功成名就 你懂的
I wanted to be successful, too, you know.
嗯 蒂姆
Sure, Tim.
我赚了很多钱…
I made a lot of money...
但你组建了一个家庭
but you made a family.
真相是…
The truth is...
高处不胜寒
it's lonely at the top.
♪ Reach with me
♪ See the sky
♪ I'll always be here for the rest of your life
♪ Sail that ocean
♪ Find that sand
♪ We know that divided we'll fall
♪ So together we stand
我很抱歉冷落了你
You know, I'm... I'm sorry we don't see each other anymore.
一个明智的人告诉过我
A very wise person once told me,
不能因为你长大了
just because you grow up
就代表你们就得分开
doesn't mean you have to grow apart.
是蒂娜吗? 是的
-Was it Tina? -Oh, yeah.
她真是太聪明了
Oh, it is crazy how smart she is.
就好像她能看穿你的灵魂
It's like she looks right into your soul.
抱歉我错过了你的毕业典礼
I'm sorry that I missed your graduations.
抱歉我错过了你的婚礼
I'm sorry I missed your one wedding.
抱歉我没能陪在你身边
I'm sorry I wasn't there for you.
♪ Side by side
♪ Hand in hand
♪ We speak a language no one else can understand
♪ Hear those cheers
♪ Strike up the band
♪ We know that divided we'll fall
♪ So together we stand.
哦 塔比莎
Oh, Tabitha.
爷爷?
Gramps?
奶奶? 妈妈?
Nana? Mom?
哦 不!
Oh, no!
天啊 塔比莎
Oh, my gosh, Tabitha.
你做得很好
You did such a great job.
真是太没礼貌了
Well, that's just horribly rude of you all.
现在 请大家
Come on, everybody.
起立鼓掌
Uh, how about a standing ovation?
很好
Very good.
他们被控制了!
They're zombies!
我们做到了!
We did it!
"宝宝革命"已经开始了
The baby revolution has begun.
不再需要伪装了
No more need for costumes.
谁想要蛋糕?
Who wants cake?
哦 我的天啊
Oh, my gosh.
宝宝们 庆祝吧
Happy B-Day, everybody.
爸爸 泰德叔叔
Daddy, Uncle Ted.
你们在哪里?
Come in. Where are you?
给你 姐妹
Here you go, sis.
我已经试过了 它是安全的
Now, I already used this, so I know it's safe.
谢谢
Thanks.
你会说话?
Wait. Are you t-talking?
我知道 这很奇怪
I know. It's pretty weird, isn't it?
天啊 你会说话!
Oh, my gosh, you're talking!
这是个紧急情况
It's an emergency.
我在执行"宝宝公司"的秘密任务
I'm on a supersecret mission from BabyCorp.
爸爸说的都是真的?
You mean Dad's stories are true?
这套制服说明了一切
That's what the suit says.
我看起来怎么样?
How do I look?
不是吧!
No way!
现在我联系不上爸爸和泰德了
Now, I can't get ahold of Dad or Uncle Ted,
所以我需要你的帮助 姐姐
so I need your help, big sis.
爸爸在这的吗?
Wait, wait. Dad's here?
他们一直都在这里
They've been here the whole time.
在哪? 我没有太多时间解释
-Where? -I don't have much time to explain,
但博士也是个宝宝
but Dr. Armstrong is a baby.
一肚子坏水的宝宝
A very bad, bad baby.
很快 世界就是宝宝的啦
Soon, the world is gonna be our playground.
哟!
Whee!
现在我们可以报复家长啦
Now we can make parents do whatever we want.
太棒了! 是啊!
Awesome! Yeah!
没有规则
No more rules.
再见 爸爸妈妈
Sayonara, Mama and Papa.
是的
Yeah.
妈妈? 爸爸?
-Mom? -Dad?
爷爷?
Grandpa?
哇 这也太荒诞了
Whoa. Are you kidding me?
我们得把关闭它 防止扩散到全球
We need to shut it down before it goes global.
是的 我们该怎么做?
-Yeah. -What are we gonna do?
我们得找到那个不知名的"机器"
Okay, we need to find the big whatchamacallit
它控制着父母的手机
that controls the parents' phones.
服务器 是的 是的
-The server. -Yes. Yes.
学校里有那种东西吗?
Is there a big one of those whatsits at school?
嗯 让我看看
Uh, let's see.
服务器非常热 所以需要通风道
Well, servers get really hot, so you need air ducts.
说的真对
Now you're thinking!
在橡子树上!
Which intersect at the acorn!
优秀 快
-A-plus! -Come on.
往这走
This way.
机会来了
Opportunity knocks.
首先 我们得短暂的补给
First, we need to make a quick pit stop.
你的时间已经结束了
Your time has concluded.
看来就这样了
It looks like this is it, Tim.
嘿 至少我们有过
Well, hey, at least we have
友情修复的珍贵时刻
these last final precious moments together.
珍贵的 宝贵的!
Precious. Precious!
-哦 对 珍贵的 -宝贵的!
Oh, right. Precious. Precious!
好样的
That's my girl.
谢谢你!
Thank you.
蒂娜?
Tina?
蒂娜 回复 我是爸爸
Tina, Tina, come in. It's Daddy.
爸爸! 听着 我们得关闭服务器
Daddy! Listen, we have to shut down the server.
在橡子树里 啊
-It's in the acorn. -Whoa.
这太奇怪了
This is so weird.
让我来驾驶
I call shotgun.
我要做前座
I called shotgun
用法来源于美国西部 过去驾车行路遇到劫匪 需要副驾驶手拿武器自卫
快 到橡子树那儿去!
Quick, to the acorn!
抓紧 伙计
Hold on to your chaps, pal.
哇!
Whoa!
哦 不!
Oh, no!
胶水!
Glue!
呀! 仙尘! 啊哈
Yah! Pixie dust! Aha.
不错 宝贝 对
-Yeah, baby. -Yes.
什么?
Wha...?
这是哪?
Where'd I go?
啊! 我喜欢你的睡衣
-Whoa! -I like your pajamas.
你要去哪里?
Where are you going?
我为自己是普通人而自豪
I'm proud to be a yellow.
我喜欢你的小马
I like your pony.
谢谢你!
Thank you.
什么?
What?
啊 啊 不 不
Ah, ah, ah. No, no, no.
现在打开这个大坚果
Now let's crack that big nut.
它要扩散到全世界了
Oh, no. It's about to go worldwide.
我们要怎么上去?
How are we gonna get up there?
讲真的? 你有勇气
-Really? -Well, you got grit.
我接受
I'll give you that.
进取心 非常令人钦佩
Gumption, even. Very admirable.
但是 很烦人
And yet, uh, annoying.
烦人 嗯
Quite annoying. Yeah.
我得阻止你
I'm gonna have to, you know, uh, stop you.
倒给我胶水
Glue me, glue me, glue me.
马儿拖住他
Precious, sic him.
你太渺小 也太慢了
You're too little and too late.
坏宠物
Ah, ba-bad dog.
学校不允许养宠物 小宝贝!
-Pets aren't allowed in school. -Aah! Precious!
还有你 我的小保镖
And you, my pudgy protégé.
快! 跑!
Go, go, go, go! Move! Move!
给了你如此优厚的条件
I offered you the world.
我们本可以成为搭档的
We could have been partners.
我有比搭档更好的友情
I've got something better than a partner.
我有一个哥哥 -耶!
-I have a brother. -Yeah!
放手 不 你放手
-Let go. -No, you let go.
哇 说的真对
Wow. Point taken.
什么? 这是怎么了
What? What's going on?
嘿 那是我的休闲战服
Hey, that's my leisure suit.
她穿起来更好看
It looks better on her.
举起手来 放下"武器"
Hands up, diapers down.
事情要变得奇怪了
Things are about to get weird.
不愧我的女儿们!
Yeah, that's my girls!
他真的是爸爸? 是的
-That's really Dad? -Yep.
我跟他说了很多心里话
I said a lot of stuff to that kid.
真是一次家庭聚会
Well, quite the family reunion.
人越多越好
Uh, the more the merrier.
不如叫家长们加入吧 哦,不
-I say let's call your parents. -Oh, no.
啊哦 好的
-Uh-oh. -Okay.
家长们 拥抱他们…到死
Mommy and Daddy, let's hug 'em--to death.
别担心我们 快进服务器
Oh, don't worry about us. Get to the server.
蒂娜 走吧!
Go, Tina, go!
嘿! 你能做到的
-Hey! -You got this, Tina.
快下来
Get down from there.
去拿他的棒棒糖!
Go for his lollies!
别碰我的"宝贝"
Never touch another man's pony.
留在这 别动
Here. Stick around. Stick around.
我们现在该怎么办?
Uh, Tim, what do we do now?!
别动 也许他们就看不到我们
Don't move. Maybe they won't see us.
他们看得见我们
They see us, Tim. They see us.
你动了吗? 我没动
Did you move? I didn't move.
你没骗我吧?
Really, Tim?
嘿 这里太高了吧
Oh. Hey, that's a little too high now.
不要往下看 看着前方
Don't look down. Look straight ahead, okay?
有锁
It's locked.
要我帮你(解锁)吗
Can I give you a hand?
当然 我是开玩笑的
Of course, I mean that facetiously,
手就像是…一个(钥匙)关键
because the hand acts as a... as a key.
不 不 不
No, no. No, no, no.
谢谢 姐姐
Thanks, sis.
离我的服务器远点
Stay away from my server.
关掉它 塔比莎
What are you doing?
别这样做 求你了
What are you doing? No, no, no! No!
不要啊
Don't do that.
哦 不!
Oh, no!
抱抱 抱抱爷爷
-Hugs. -Hug Grandpa.
婴儿潮
Living Boomers
指出生率大幅度提升的现象
今晚是老一辈的天下
It's Night of the Living Boomers.
爸爸 快停下! 拥抱
-Dad, stop! -Hugs.
回来 退后 你们这些小坏蛋
Back. Back, you little monsters.
你给我退后 糖心老头
You back off, candy pants.
哈!你过来啊
Ha! Got your nose.
精准命中!
Oh, right in the breadbasket!
噢! 哈!
-Ow! -Ha!
-把他权限封了 -啊
-Knocked his block off. -Ah, poopy.
蒂娜 我弄明白啦
Tina, I think I got it. Yes!
不要按那个按钮 啊!
Don't hit that button. Don't hit that button. Aah!
噢!噢!
Ow! Ooh!
进入 不! 停下!
-And... enter. -No, no! Stop it!
省省吧
Cut it out.
看看你干的好事 灭火喷洒
Look what you made me do. The fire alarm.
该死的 爸爸!
-Darn it. -Dad!
泰德! 拉响火灾报警器!
Uncle Ted! Pull the fire alarm!
姑娘们需要帮助 别亲我!
-The girls need help. -No kissies!
她们需要我们帮忙
The girls need us.
时间到了 "哈比人"
Time's up, halflings.
巨大的怪兽!
Great galloping gargoyles!
快去拉响火警报警器!
Tim! Get to the fire alarm!
我会拖住他们
I'll hold them back.
喷洒水下来吧
Make it rain, baby.
我正在弄
I'm on it.
怎么了?
What's the matter?
是不是很尴尬?
You can't handle the awkward phase?
马科斯…爸爸 加油!
Go, Marcos... uh, Dad. Go!
我来了!
I'm back!
再来一轮怎么样 硬汉?来吧!
How about another round, you tough guy? Come on!
别闹了
Ow. Stop it.
我还有双手
I still got these.
快把我妹妹放下来
You put my sister down.
宝宝革命日终将会成功
B-Day will happen, whether you like it or not.
你不能通过!
You shall not pass!
你不能通过
Uh, you shall not pass.
不! 停下
No! Stop passing.
干的不错 爸爸!
Yeah, Dad!
来啦!
Way to go!
就这点?
That's it?
对哦 为什么呢? 学校开销很大
That's right. Why? What? The school's expensive.
我不得不削减开支
I had to cut costs someplace.
这不起作用
Oh, no. It's not working.
你拉对了吗?
Did you pull it right?
你还能怎么拉?
How else you gonna pull it?
你会发现我是对的
You'll see I'm right.
我会告诉每一个人
I'll show everybody.
家长掌权的时代已经过去了
The age of parents is over.
耶 耶 耶
Yay, yay, yay.
你看我的祝酒词怎么样?
How about you watch me have a little toast?
敬宝宝革命和我自己
To the baby revolution and to me.
该"糖果火山"了 嗯,嗯
-It's time for the candy volcano... -Mmm, mmm.
-味道不错 -厄运来袭!
-Oh, that's good. -and Of doom!
你在干什么?
What are you doing? What are you doing?
不! 不!
No, no, no! No!
不 不 不
Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
不 不 "进球"
-No, no, no. -Boom shakalaka?
别在弄了!
Don't do that!
哇!
Whoa!
哦 不!
Oh, no!
塔比莎!
Tabitha!
谁快来帮帮我
No! Someone help me, please!
塔比莎 稍等!
Tabitha, hang on!
泰德 甩我上去
Ted, I need upsies--now.
爸爸 救救我!
Dad, help me!
看看你
Look at you.
聪明 自强
You're smart. You're strong.
你不需要父母
You don't need parents.
他们能给你带来什么?
What can they possibly offer you?
无条件的爱
How about unconditional love?
这就是原因 不 不
-That's what. -No, no, no. No.
再会 不 不
-Sayonara. -No, no, no. No.
塔比莎!
Tabitha!
我要掉下去了! 塔比莎!
-I'm gonna fall! -Tabitha!
坚持住!
Hang on!
我来了
I got you. I got you.
我接住你了
I got you, Tabitha.
终于得到你了
I got you.
好样的 哥哥
That's my big brother.
谢谢 马科斯莱比
Thanks, Marcos Lightspeed.
你不是说过要保持距离?
I thought we both had to grow up.
慢慢来 我还离不开您
Well, let's not grow up too fast.
我爱您 爸爸
I love you, Dad.
我爱你 塔比莎•邓普顿
I love you, Tabitha Templeton.
哦 你看到了吗?
Aw. You see that?
而你想把这一切都夺走
And you wanted to take it all away.
要去哪里? 回家
-Where you going? -Home.
要知道 你不能永远停留在过去
You know, Doc, childhood doesn't last forever,
亲情天长地久
but family sure does.
泰德叔叔! 接住我!
Uncle Ted! Heads up!
啊!
Woo-hoo!
我们赢了! 准备披萨派对吧
We win! Get ready to order some pizzas.
对应01:13:19的台词
Cut to our pizza party.
哇 哦!
Woo-hoo!
酷!
Cool!
太好了!
Huzzah!
呼呼!
真不错
Oh, sweet.
(失主找到前)
先保管好
He who findeth keepeth.
妈妈 爸爸 我好想你
Mommy, Daddy, I missed you so much.
噢 噢 耶!
Ooh, ooh, ooh. Yay!
儿子!
Junior!
"胶水"!
Glue!
毛发好软
So soft.
我们要去哪里?
Where are we going?
不错 邓普顿家
Not bad, Templetons.
耶 邓普顿万岁
Woo-hoo! Yay, Templetons.
是的 任务完成
Yeah, mission accomplished.
阻止了博士只是附加任务
And as a bonus, we stopped Armstrong, too.
嗯? 什么?
-Huh? -What?
我真正的任务是让你们复合
My real mission was getting you two back together.
对应00:12:04的台词
It's like, "F-minus. See me after class."
"满分 课后嘉奖"
A-plus! See me after class.
所以你从没辞职?
Wait, so you never actually quit?
不  嗯
-Nope. -Huh.
干得漂亮
Well played.
我喜欢公私分明
I don't like to mix the two,
工作在后
but I will say it was never business.
对应00:22:48的台词
It's not personal. It's business, Leslie.
家庭优先
It was always personal.
你知道吗 孩子?
You know what, kid?
你是我见过最好的老板
You're the best boss I ever had.
谢谢你 长官
Thank you, chief.
蒂姆! 你真的来了
Tim! You actually made it.
是的 你从不会让我失望
-Yeah. -I mean, I knew you'd make it.
泰迪 泰迪 你在这里
-Teddy. -Teddy, you're here.
你衣服怎么了 额…
-And look what you're wearing. -Uh...
你表演的太好了
Sweetheart, I cried.
然后我就失忆了
Then I went blank.
大家聚在一起拍个照
Oh, come on. Every-Everyone get together.
纪念一下 准备要拍啦
This... We got to get this. Here we go.
爸爸,不! 什么?
-Dad, no! -No! -What?
♪ We know that
♪ Divided we'll fall
♪ So together we stand
♪ We know that divided we'll fall
♪ So together we stand.
耶 塔比莎! 唱的真好听
-Yay, Tabitha! -That was beautiful!
为你的歌声疯狂!
The crowd goes wild!
谢谢大家!
Thank you. Thank you.
嘿 宝贝
Aw, hey, Precious.
你真了不起
You're amazing.
真希望泰迪能在这
Oh, I wish Teddy could have been here.
我也是这样想
Yeah, I know. Me, too.
嗯
Hmm.
嘿 我只是…
Hey, I was just...
圣诞快乐 蒂姆
Merry Christmas, Tim.
很抱歉我没能和你在一起
I'm sorry I couldn't be there with you,
但是请欣赏这个
but please enjoy this
合适而不奢华的礼物
inappropriately lavish gift instead.
你给了我最好的礼物
You've given me the greatest gift of all.
你
You.
爱你 世界上最好的兄弟
Love, the best brother in the world.
注: 快躲
P.S. Duck.
正中红心 莱斯利!
In your face, Leslie!
雪战开始了 琳赛!
Hey. Oh, it is on, Lindsey!
不 不 不要 来吧!
-No. No, no, no, no. Don't, don't, don't. -Come here!
我比你年轻
I'm younger than you.
你更容易被砸中
You're a bigger target.
我对你太好了!
I got you so good!
不 你没有 你扔歪啦!
-No, you didn't. -Aah! You missed me!
你和我想的一样吗?
Are you thinking what I'm thinking?
伏击 不错
-Ambush. -Exactly.
噢! 偷袭!
-Ow! -Sneak attack!
看到他们打闹真是太好了
Oh, isn't it great to see them fighting again?
最后
Finally.
你不接电话吗?
Shouldn't you pick up?
不 我们有家事要办
Nah, we got some family business.
啊! 好!
Woo-hoo! Yeah!
蒂娜 我们有个新任务给你
Tina, we have another assignment for you.
我在听
I'm listening.
奶奶端菜来啦!
Grandma's coming in hot!
你要尝点吗 爷爷? 所有人 去抓小马!
-You want some of Grandpa? -Everyone, get Tagalong Teddy!
对 打到了!
-It's true. -Gotcha!
你不能停止时间
You can't stop time.
但可以抓住生命中的下一个机会
But every once in a while, you get a second chance.
我会抓到你的!
I'm gonna get you!
不要太过纠结于过去的失败
So, even though you're only a kid once...
除非你能返老还童
well, unless you get to be a kid twice,
有些天方夜谭 扯远了
which is really weird, to be honest,
重点是你总有一天要面对现实
but the point is you have to grow up sometime.
那时别忘了陪伴和照顾你的亲人
And you should always be nice to your brother.
你真贴心 爸爸
Ah, that was really sweet, Daddy.
这对我的报告很有帮助
That'll be great for my report.
好吧 所以…就这样
Okay, so... so that's it, then.
其实 还有一件小事
Well, actually, there's one more little thing.
妈妈?爸爸?
Mama? Papa?
哦,我的儿子
Oh, my son.
你回家
You came home.
哦 是的
Oh, yeah. Right.
好的 老爸 现在
Okay, Pops. Now.
剧 终
♪ Catch my eye
♪ Take my hand
♪ This bond is tighter than we ever planned
♪ Give me courage
♪ So I can land
♪ We know that divided we'll fall
♪ So together we stand
♪ Climb with me
♪ Share my dreams
♪ Tomorrow's brighter
♪ Than it's ever been
♪ Fear no danger
♪ Make big plans
♪ We know that divided we'll fall
♪ So together we stand
♪ Laugh and cry with me
♪ Fly that high with me
♪ See the sunset and the sunrise
♪ The world looks so good through our eyes
♪ Like the moon
♪ And stars at night
♪ Rest your head
♪ Tell me your thoughts
♪ Everything I have and call mine
♪ Is all yours
♪ Sail that ocean
♪ Find that sand
♪ We know that divided we'll fall
♪ So together we stand
♪ Reach with me
♪ See the sky
♪ I'll always be here for the rest of your life
♪ Side by side
♪ Hand in hand
♪ We speak a language no one else can understand
♪ Hear those cheers
♪ Strike up the band
♪ We know that divided we'll fall
♪ So together we stand
♪ We know that
♪ Divided we'll fall
♪ So together we stand.